<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Gianluca Fiore</title>
    <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Gianluca Fiore</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:04:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flying is terrible</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/flying-is-terrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:04:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/flying-is-terrible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never loved flying. I tolerated it in the beginning. Then grew fond of it. Until it became the worst possible way of transportation there is. Now I am considering renouncing flying altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sounded a bit dramatic, didn&amp;rsquo;t it? Oh well, imagine how strong is my frustration with flying then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Premise: I am an old flyer. I started boarding planes in the mid 1990s. Before low cost airlines, before the concept of going through an international hub to reach your final destination was born. If you wanted to fly back then, 99% of the times it was your national flag carrier airline, within Europe, and for longer flights there were alliances that meant you were sent to another national airline somewhere closer to your final destination. It was normal to have 2, max 3 flights to reach even the most remote location in the world. You flew from your local airport to a national/international hub, then to the other company&amp;rsquo;s hub, then to your final destination. Services like seat reservation, sizeable hand luggage, a simple meal, water/coffee/tea/soft drinks were all naturally included in the price of your tickets. Even in 30 minutes flight a sweet or cookie was given without costs. On some companies, beer and wine were also freely given with the cheapest ticket.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bali</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/bali/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 14:11:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/bali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;see-bali-once--and-no-more&#34;&gt;See Bali once &amp;hellip; and no more&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bali. Just the word evokes lush forests, rice terraces, yoga, coffee houses, dawn treks, and digital nomading. I didn&amp;rsquo;t particularly go for any of those but would be unfair to assert that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t captivated a bit by each. I found them all, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t fully satisfied by any.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rewind to 2021. Coronavirus pandemic and all that. I was going to travel to Bali for the first time in my life during summer but touristic visa was not allowed for those that weren&amp;rsquo;t from a handful of south-east Asian countries. Only a pricey business visa. Me and my girlfriend decided then to postpone the trip to the following year. We went instead to Mexico, which was amazing. I should write about it one day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Pelé</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/on-pele/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 11:04:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/on-pele/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-king-and-the-god-are-gone&#34;&gt;The King and the God are gone&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pelé was a totem. And a scary one at that. For a kid growing up in Naples during the 80s, Pelé was not a tangible experience but a myth already. Somebody who we would all compare to, as the archetype of the great footballer from South America.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was a scary figure. Scary because for a city being dragged to the top of the league, twice, by Maradona, Pelé was the only one we could possibly believe being better than our God, Diego. Fans used to chant &amp;ldquo;Maradona is better than Pelé&amp;rdquo; and, while perhaps true, it was a chant born out of fear rather than proud.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fountain Pen Creator</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/fountain-pen-creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 12:54:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/fountain-pen-creator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to see how this blog has been &lt;strong&gt;neglected&lt;/strong&gt; for a long time. My fault, obviously. Also &lt;strong&gt;my choice&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Point being, I’ve been barely thinking and working with my coding projects&#xA;since about a year. Why? I got &lt;strong&gt;disillusioned&lt;/strong&gt;. I lost interest in modern&#xA;coding practices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me be clear: I do &lt;strong&gt;like coding&lt;/strong&gt; and I will be coding in my spare time,&#xA;occasionally, forever, probably. I am going to use my coding knowledge in my&#xA;future career(s) as an advantage point and to automate my work. Coding isn’t&#xA;going to disappear from my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freecodecamp: There and Back Again</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/freecodecamp-there-and-back-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 15:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/freecodecamp-there-and-back-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, first of all, sorry for not updating about my progresses on Frontend development through Freecodecamp curriculum but there were basically none since last May. Why? Work got in the way, with a larger role and more duties taking over little by little the energy I had to focus on coding after work. First reason.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Second reason, health issues. I&amp;rsquo;ve been battling with the most pernicious kind of backpain since spring and it intensified around June, when it became a routine to wake up in the middle of the night due to the pain, spend half an hour trying to get back to sleep, get up much earlier than due (like 6-6:30) and spending the rest of the day in a perennial tired state. Rinse and repeat the day after. For weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appreciation</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/appreciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 11:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/appreciation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been surprised, even amused, by the show of affection friends show in myself. Caring about myself has never been a high priority for me, I admit, so I emotionally recoil whenever an external being cares about my wellbeing more than me. I cannot comprehend it, on an emotional level of course as logically it is natural for friends to care about each other.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What surprises me the most is the long-lasting effect I may have on people who I have barely crossed their paths during my life. People who I shared 20 words on a party 8 months ago, people who are friends of a friend that don&amp;rsquo;t talk among themselves much either, go figure with me. People who work at my same place and that we bump into each other once every 2 weeks. These kind of people. Not even acquaintances. Less than that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back To Naples</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/back-to-naples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 11:04:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/back-to-naples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I went back to my &lt;strong&gt;hometown&lt;/strong&gt;, Naples, for New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve. Meeting with family and showing the city to girlfriend. A very enjoyable week, I have to say, fun, drinks, good food, visiting as a tourist your old home and rejoining with 2 lovely cats at home :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trip reinforced my &lt;strong&gt;love-hate&lt;/strong&gt; relationship with Naples. The food is &lt;strong&gt;outstanding&lt;/strong&gt;, it is really, really hard to find another city with same quality food as Naples, no doubts. People are generally warm and welcoming, open for a chat at any moment and with a hint of humanity that you don&amp;rsquo;t get that often in north Italy (your mileage may vary, of course). The city is artistically rich, beautiful in a decadent way, there are still plenty of unknown to tourists places to discover, the view from Posillipo or the Vesuvio is &lt;strong&gt;breathtaking&lt;/strong&gt; and art is everywhere around you, as usual in Italy. &lt;strong&gt;Cheap&lt;/strong&gt; prices to eat out, a new, modern metro system and the best pizza in the world complete the offer of the city to visitors. It is also nearly impossible to find another city in the world which has the same quantity and quality of day trip to make: from Pompeii (and Ercolano), to Vesuvio, to Capri, Sorrento, the Amalfi coast with Positano and Caserta with its &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;italian Versailles&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
