<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pink Floyd on Gianluca Fiore</title>
    <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/pink-floyd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pink Floyd on Gianluca Fiore</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:04:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/pink-floyd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Favourite Pink Floyd songs</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/favourite-pink-floyd-songs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:04:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/favourite-pink-floyd-songs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always been a huge Pink Floyd fan. Despite what my Spotify stats tell (which I listen to Nick Cave more), Pink Floyd have always had a special place in my music and life. They are the band that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to classify, or rate, nor rank. They are outside every category. They stay on their own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I sat down the other day and thought of the best Pink Floyd songs, or at least my favourite ones. I came up with a list, but soon enough scratched that. I thought it would be far more interesting and original to list only their songs that somehow elicit specific images in my head when I listen to them. A few bands manage to do it, and Pink Floyd have the most songs that I associate a precise vibe and image with. These images are not necessarily associated with what the song is about; they are just what they make me think about and feel. It is a completely personal list, wholly different from anybody else&amp;rsquo;s. Still, I find it curious how these associations were born and why, and I thought it worth to write them here for posterity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
