<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Gianluca Fiore</title>
    <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Gianluca Fiore</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:04:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flying is terrible</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/flying-is-terrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:04:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/flying-is-terrible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never loved flying. I tolerated it in the beginning. Then grew fond of it. Until it became the worst possible way of transportation there is. Now I am considering renouncing flying altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sounded a bit dramatic, didn&amp;rsquo;t it? Oh well, imagine how strong is my frustration with flying then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Premise: I am an old flyer. I started boarding planes in the mid 1990s. Before low cost airlines, before the concept of going through an international hub to reach your final destination was born. If you wanted to fly back then, 99% of the times it was your national flag carrier airline, within Europe, and for longer flights there were alliances that meant you were sent to another national airline somewhere closer to your final destination. It was normal to have 2, max 3 flights to reach even the most remote location in the world. You flew from your local airport to a national/international hub, then to the other company&amp;rsquo;s hub, then to your final destination. Services like seat reservation, sizeable hand luggage, a simple meal, water/coffee/tea/soft drinks were all naturally included in the price of your tickets. Even in 30 minutes flight a sweet or cookie was given without costs. On some companies, beer and wine were also freely given with the cheapest ticket.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back To Naples</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/back-to-naples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 11:04:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/back-to-naples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I went back to my &lt;strong&gt;hometown&lt;/strong&gt;, Naples, for New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve. Meeting with family and showing the city to girlfriend. A very enjoyable week, I have to say, fun, drinks, good food, visiting as a tourist your old home and rejoining with 2 lovely cats at home :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trip reinforced my &lt;strong&gt;love-hate&lt;/strong&gt; relationship with Naples. The food is &lt;strong&gt;outstanding&lt;/strong&gt;, it is really, really hard to find another city with same quality food as Naples, no doubts. People are generally warm and welcoming, open for a chat at any moment and with a hint of humanity that you don&amp;rsquo;t get that often in north Italy (your mileage may vary, of course). The city is artistically rich, beautiful in a decadent way, there are still plenty of unknown to tourists places to discover, the view from Posillipo or the Vesuvio is &lt;strong&gt;breathtaking&lt;/strong&gt; and art is everywhere around you, as usual in Italy. &lt;strong&gt;Cheap&lt;/strong&gt; prices to eat out, a new, modern metro system and the best pizza in the world complete the offer of the city to visitors. It is also nearly impossible to find another city in the world which has the same quantity and quality of day trip to make: from Pompeii (and Ercolano), to Vesuvio, to Capri, Sorrento, the Amalfi coast with Positano and Caserta with its &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;italian Versailles&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
