<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Healthcare on Gianluca Fiore</title>
    <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/healthcare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Healthcare on Gianluca Fiore</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 10:54:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/healthcare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HCA Florida</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/hca-florida/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 10:54:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/hca-florida/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Client&lt;/strong&gt;: HCA Florida&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job&lt;/strong&gt;: content authoring, technical writing, website designing&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;: redesigning and refreshing content of the HCA Florida hospitals&#xA;and doctors websites&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sample link&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hcafloridahealthcare.com&#34;&gt;HCA Florida Healthcare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audience&lt;/strong&gt;: general public and patients&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More info&lt;/strong&gt;: the CMS is Sitecore. I was assigned a few mock-ups of the final&#xA;pages and had to build the blocks of each page, as widgets, into the Sitecore&#xA;system. Content was provided in form of images, links to videos, and plain&#xA;text. My role was largely one of formatting text according to the mock-ups,&#xA;fitting the images, testing the final pages, and think of SEO changes to be&#xA;made before the final publishing of the website. A spanish translation was also&#xA;underway but I was not involved. The most difficult part of the project was in&#xA;editing and adapting the content to the widgets in Sitecore; often the text was&#xA;a &amp;ldquo;wishlist&amp;rdquo; of what should appear on a given place on the page but it didn&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;quite fit, conceptually and typographically. I spent a long time revising these&#xA;parts and coming up with modifications that would suit better the overall&#xA;design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
