<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Gianluca Fiore</title>
    <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Gianluca Fiore</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 10:54:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HCA Florida</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/hca-florida/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 10:54:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/hca-florida/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Client&lt;/strong&gt;: HCA Florida&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Job&lt;/strong&gt;: content authoring, technical writing, website designing&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;: redesigning and refreshing content of the HCA Florida hospitals&#xA;and doctors websites&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sample link&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hcafloridahealthcare.com&#34;&gt;HCA Florida Healthcare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audience&lt;/strong&gt;: general public and patients&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More info&lt;/strong&gt;: the CMS is Sitecore. I was assigned a few mock-ups of the final&#xA;pages and had to build the blocks of each page, as widgets, into the Sitecore&#xA;system. Content was provided in form of images, links to videos, and plain&#xA;text. My role was largely one of formatting text according to the mock-ups,&#xA;fitting the images, testing the final pages, and think of SEO changes to be&#xA;made before the final publishing of the website. A spanish translation was also&#xA;underway but I was not involved. The most difficult part of the project was in&#xA;editing and adapting the content to the widgets in Sitecore; often the text was&#xA;a &amp;ldquo;wishlist&amp;rdquo; of what should appear on a given place on the page but it didn&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;quite fit, conceptually and typographically. I spent a long time revising these&#xA;parts and coming up with modifications that would suit better the overall&#xA;design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Story</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/my-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 10:59:46 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/my-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was born in Naples, Italy. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know it, it&amp;rsquo;s a place where art, criminality, religiousity, awesome food, the best pizza in the world, strong coffee, the sea, 2 volcanos and greek+roman+christian civilitazions meet and thrive(d) for thousands of years. Not an easy place to be born, nor one that won&amp;rsquo;t leave you with marks, positive and negatives, for all your life. It certainly did not leave me without an indelible impression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Travel Solo</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/how-to-travel-solo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 11:24:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/how-to-travel-solo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the first book, of which I was no more than a contributor, &lt;a href=&#34;../your-first-year-in-code&#34;&gt;Your First Year In Code&lt;/a&gt;, I decided that was fine and actually great fun to write and publish books so I wrote another one :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This one much more personal, about my passion for traveling and in particular to travel alone, something that I have been doing for more than 20 years, nearly each year: How To Travel Solo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your First Year In Code</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/your-first-year-in-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 11:24:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/your-first-year-in-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With my extreme surprise, but also extreme happiness, I published a book! I say&#xA;surprise because I didn&amp;rsquo;t plan to but heard about the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;https://isaaclyman.com/&#34;&gt;Isaac&#xA;Lyman&lt;/a&gt; and his idea of writing a guide book for new&#xA;and aspiring developers, not too techincal but instead full of advices and&#xA;knowledge that is geared towards those who are approaching the profession, or&#xA;recently started it. The main goal of Isaac&amp;rsquo;s idea was to write a book that&#xA;would teach you a few non technical things that we learnt in our first 1-2&#xA;years as developers and we truly wished we knew from the beginning instead.&#xA;Sort of jumpstarting your career.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
