<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog posts on Gianluca Fiore</title>
    <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog posts on Gianluca Fiore</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:04:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Favourite Pink Floyd songs</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/favourite-pink-floyd-songs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:04:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/favourite-pink-floyd-songs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always been a huge Pink Floyd fan. Despite what my Spotify stats tell (which I listen to Nick Cave more), Pink Floyd have always had a special place in my music and life. They are the band that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to classify, or rate, nor rank. They are outside every category. They stay on their own.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I sat down the other day and thought of the best Pink Floyd songs, or at least my favourite ones. I came up with a list, but soon enough scratched that. I thought it would be far more interesting and original to list only their songs that somehow elicit specific images in my head when I listen to them. A few bands manage to do it, and Pink Floyd have the most songs that I associate a precise vibe and image with. These images are not necessarily associated with what the song is about; they are just what they make me think about and feel. It is a completely personal list, wholly different from anybody else&amp;rsquo;s. Still, I find it curious how these associations were born and why, and I thought it worth to write them here for posterity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flying is terrible</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/flying-is-terrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:04:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/flying-is-terrible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never loved flying. I tolerated it in the beginning. Then grew fond of it. Until it became the worst possible way of transportation there is. Now I am considering renouncing flying altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sounded a bit dramatic, didn&amp;rsquo;t it? Oh well, imagine how strong is my frustration with flying then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Premise: I am an old flyer. I started boarding planes in the mid 1990s. Before low cost airlines, before the concept of going through an international hub to reach your final destination was born. If you wanted to fly back then, 99% of the times it was your national flag carrier airline, within Europe, and for longer flights there were alliances that meant you were sent to another national airline somewhere closer to your final destination. It was normal to have 2, max 3 flights to reach even the most remote location in the world. You flew from your local airport to a national/international hub, then to the other company&amp;rsquo;s hub, then to your final destination. Services like seat reservation, sizeable hand luggage, a simple meal, water/coffee/tea/soft drinks were all naturally included in the price of your tickets. Even in 30 minutes flight a sweet or cookie was given without costs. On some companies, beer and wine were also freely given with the cheapest ticket.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bali</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/bali/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 14:11:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/bali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bali. Just the word evokes lush forests, rice terraces, yoga, coffee houses, dawn treks, and digital nomading. I didn&amp;rsquo;t particularly go for any of those but would be unfair to assert that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t captivated a bit by each. I found them all, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t fully satisfied by any.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rewind to 2021. Coronavirus pandemic and all that. I was going to travel to Bali for the first time in my life during summer but touristic visa was not allowed for those that weren&amp;rsquo;t from a handful of south-east Asian countries. Only a pricey business visa. Me and my girlfriend decided then to postpone the trip to the following year. We went instead to Mexico, which was amazing. I should write about it one day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Pelé</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/on-pele/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 11:04:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/on-pele/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The King and the God are gone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pelé was a totem. And a scary one at that. For a kid growing up in Naples during the 80s, Pelé was not a tangible experience but a myth already. Somebody who we would all compare to, as the archetype of the great footballer from South America.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was a scary figure. Scary because for a city being dragged to the top of the league, twice, by Maradona, Pelé was the only one we could possibly believe being better than our God, Diego. Fans used to chant &amp;ldquo;Maradona is better than Pelé&amp;rdquo; and, while perhaps true, it was a chant born out of fear rather than proud.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most Meetings Are Useless</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/most-meetings-are-useless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 11:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/most-meetings-are-useless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I rarely had a useful meeting. I can count on the fingers of one hand the truly important, making-things-go-forward meetings I had in the last year. And yet, I regularly have to endure them. Daily.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a Technical Writer, you&amp;rsquo;d expect meetings to be worthwhile sources of info and insight. And don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, they can be. But they aren&amp;rsquo;t in the form that most companies hold them nowadays. I am largely referring to the daily stand-ups that a good share of companies nowadays have implemented (read, forced). Most of these meetings are managers asking for updates, then each member of the team talking about their &amp;ldquo;stream&amp;rdquo; and what are their progresses or lack thereof. This for a good 15 minutes, usually. Sometimes 20. Then the manager tries to micromanage everybody or asks stupid questions because no one apparently puts managers that know what their subordinate do every day in charge anymore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulse 15 update after one year</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/pulse-15-update-after-one-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 14:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/pulse-15-update-after-one-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote about the Pulse 15 in &lt;a href=&#34;../pulse-15-review&#34;&gt;my previous review&lt;/a&gt;. Usually I don&amp;rsquo;t review what I buy, neither here nor elsewhere, but I made an exception for this laptop as it was from a small company and geared towards Linux users. Both things I care a lot about when purchasing technology.&#xA;If you are interested in purchasing it, the Pulse 15 is still available at Tuxedocomputers, you may want to &lt;a href=&#34;../pulse-15-review&#34;&gt;head there&lt;/a&gt; and read that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulse 15 Review</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/pulse-15-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 14:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/pulse-15-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a long time Linux user (over 20 years), the quest for a perfect Linux laptop experience has been going on for most of those years. I went through a tiny Asus EEEPc back in the mid 2000s, which served me well for the very limited purposes it could manage (the Atom processors were anything but speedy&amp;hellip;). For running Linux with a window manager and writing, browsing and listening to music it was fine. It supported Linux well but was far below the level of performances that the contemporary Windows laptops could achieve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fountain Pen Creator</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/fountain-pen-creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 12:54:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/fountain-pen-creator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to see how this blog has been &lt;strong&gt;neglected&lt;/strong&gt; for a long time. My fault, obviously. Also &lt;strong&gt;my choice&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Point being, I’ve been barely thinking and working with my coding projects&#xA;since about a year. Why? I got &lt;strong&gt;disillusioned&lt;/strong&gt;. I lost interest in modern&#xA;coding practices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me be clear: I do &lt;strong&gt;like coding&lt;/strong&gt; and I will be coding in my spare time,&#xA;occasionally, forever, probably. I am going to use my coding knowledge in my&#xA;future career(s) as an advantage point and to automate my work. Coding isn’t&#xA;going to disappear from my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things I Know as of 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/things-i-know-as-of-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 18:11:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/things-i-know-as-of-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It honestly came as a surprise a &lt;a href=&#34;https://overreacted.io/things-i-dont-know-as-of-2018/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on Overreacted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://mobile.twitter.com/dan_abramov&#34;&gt;Dan Abramov&lt;/a&gt;. He lists all the things he doesn&amp;rsquo;t know as of 2018, in an attempt to &amp;ldquo;devalue&amp;rdquo; in the eyes of newbies any experienced developer by showing off the gaps in knowledge that usually we take for granted, expecially from those developers that work for big companies and who went through a harder interview process. Considering the number of likes and retweets the post received, I&amp;rsquo;m far from being the only one surprised.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freecodecamp: There and Back Again</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/freecodecamp-there-and-back-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 15:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/freecodecamp-there-and-back-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, first of all, sorry for not updating about my progresses on Frontend development through Freecodecamp curriculum but there were basically none since last May. Why? Work got in the way, with a larger role and more duties taking over little by little the energy I had to focus on coding after work. First reason.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Second reason, health issues. I&amp;rsquo;ve been battling with the most pernicious kind of backpain since spring and it intensified around June, when it became a routine to wake up in the middle of the night due to the pain, spend half an hour trying to get back to sleep, get up much earlier than due (like 6-6:30) and spending the rest of the day in a perennial tired state. Rinse and repeat the day after. For weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appreciation</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/appreciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 11:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/appreciation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been surprised, even amused, by the show of affection friends show in myself. Caring about myself has never been a high priority for me, I admit, so I emotionally recoil whenever an external being cares about my wellbeing more than me. I cannot comprehend it, on an emotional level of course as logically it is natural for friends to care about each other.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What surprises me the most is the long-lasting effect I may have on people who I have barely crossed their paths during my life. People who I shared 20 words on a party 8 months ago, people who are friends of a friend that don&amp;rsquo;t talk among themselves much either, go figure with me. People who work at my same place and that we bump into each other once every 2 weeks. These kind of people. Not even acquaintances. Less than that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freecodecamp</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/freecodecamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 21:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/freecodecamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frontend development&lt;/strong&gt; was never my area. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been more of a Backend/System Administrator. I&amp;rsquo;ve never truly grokked the idea of events, DOM, making requests elsewhere and things running outside my machine, without me giving precise instruction when to run and what arguments to accept.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yet it&amp;rsquo;s 2018 and Javascript permeates the programming world, whether we like it or not. Thus I was looking for a new challenge to keep me motivated to learn throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programming Isn&#39;t Easy</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/programming-isnt-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 14:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/programming-isnt-easy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was reading, as usual, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com&#34;&gt;Scott Hanselman&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt; and couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more on his complaining on the recent WWDC keynote asserting that programming is easy. From his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/StopSayingLearningToCodeIsEasy.aspx&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we tell folks - kids or otherwise - that programming is easy, what will they think when it gets difficult? And it will get difficult. That&amp;rsquo;s where people find themselves saying &amp;ldquo;well, I guess I&amp;rsquo;m not wired for coding. It&amp;rsquo;s just not for me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Classic Cocktails Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/classic-cocktails-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 11:33:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/classic-cocktails-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I&amp;rsquo;ve become the maintainer, and main contributor, of &lt;a href=&#34;https://duck.co/ia/view/classic_cocktails_cheat_sheet&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; DuckDuckGo&amp;rsquo;s Instant answer. It has been deployed on &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.duckduckgo.com&#34;&gt;beta.duckduckgo.com&lt;/a&gt; only so far, as it is clearly just a beta.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My passion for cocktails and carefully mixed drinks is no mistery and thus it was only natural to write such an IA for DuckDuckGo, my main search engine since a few years. It is incomplete, I only wanted to add &lt;em&gt;classic&lt;/em&gt; cocktails, not all, and there are a few doubts on the format of the recipes among the community (see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/duckduckgo/zeroclickinfo-goodies/pull/2796&#34;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt;). Namely, the sempiternal question about ounces, millilitres and parts. I side with the parts team but I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post also to call for anyone interested to express his/her opinions and submit new or better recipes. Any improvement or suggestion is appreciated, let&amp;rsquo;s get this IA out of beta!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back To Naples</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/back-to-naples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 11:04:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/back-to-naples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I went back to my &lt;strong&gt;hometown&lt;/strong&gt;, Naples, for New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve. Meeting with family and showing the city to girlfriend. A very enjoyable week, I have to say, fun, drinks, good food, visiting as a tourist your old home and rejoining with 2 lovely cats at home :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trip reinforced my &lt;strong&gt;love-hate&lt;/strong&gt; relationship with Naples. The food is &lt;strong&gt;outstanding&lt;/strong&gt;, it is really, really hard to find another city with same quality food as Naples, no doubts. People are generally warm and welcoming, open for a chat at any moment and with a hint of humanity that you don&amp;rsquo;t get that often in north Italy (your mileage may vary, of course). The city is artistically rich, beautiful in a decadent way, there are still plenty of unknown to tourists places to discover, the view from Posillipo or the Vesuvio is &lt;strong&gt;breathtaking&lt;/strong&gt; and art is everywhere around you, as usual in Italy. &lt;strong&gt;Cheap&lt;/strong&gt; prices to eat out, a new, modern metro system and the best pizza in the world complete the offer of the city to visitors. It is also nearly impossible to find another city in the world which has the same quantity and quality of day trip to make: from Pompeii (and Ercolano), to Vesuvio, to Capri, Sorrento, the Amalfi coast with Positano and Caserta with its &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;italian Versailles&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Guide To DuckDuckGo</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/a-brief-guide-to-duckduckgo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 14:34:02 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/a-brief-guide-to-duckduckgo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Or why you should be using it even if you don&amp;rsquo;t care about &lt;a href=&#34;http://donttrack.us/&#34;&gt;privacy&lt;/a&gt; or don&amp;rsquo;t know what a &lt;a href=&#34;http://dontbubble.us/&#34;&gt;search engine bubble&lt;/a&gt; may be.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s in no way a comprehensive guide nor &amp;ldquo;the best of&amp;rdquo; of what DuckDuckGo offers. Just what I find more useful and have been using so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;time&#34;&gt;Time&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;days between today and 02/28/2013&lt;/code&gt; = 16 days. Unfortunately, this uses the US month/day/year format&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;18:30 to 19:25&lt;/code&gt; = 55 minutes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;february calendar&lt;/code&gt; = print the calendar for this year&amp;rsquo;s february&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;calendar next month&lt;/code&gt; = print next month&amp;rsquo;s calendar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;travel&#34;&gt;Travel&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weather&lt;/code&gt; = weather for your current location&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;80100&lt;/code&gt; = search for the map of your postal code. Finds also matching codes in other countries. Or you can specify &lt;code&gt;80100 Germany&lt;/code&gt; to  get the result you want straight away&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;florence sunrise&lt;/code&gt; = when does the sun rises and sets in Florence? Here too it works with in the local language. Can be used as &lt;code&gt;florence sunset&lt;/code&gt; too&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;temp in new york&lt;/code&gt; = current temperature in New York&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;calling code 48&lt;/code&gt; = return to which country the given calling code corresponds to (that&amp;rsquo;s Poland btw)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;numbers-and-math&#34;&gt;Numbers and Math&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;uuid&lt;/code&gt; = generate a random unique identifier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;roman numeral MCCXXII&lt;/code&gt; = convert the roman numeral in arabic. That&amp;rsquo;s 1222, btw&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;md5 whatever&lt;/code&gt; = calculate md5 sum of &lt;code&gt;whatever&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sha whatever&lt;/code&gt; = calculate sha sum of &lt;code&gt;whatever&lt;/code&gt;. Works with &lt;code&gt;sha256&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;sha512&lt;/code&gt; too&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;goog&lt;/code&gt; = company and stock data (Google)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;roll 4d12&lt;/code&gt; = simulate rolling 4 d12 dices. D&amp;amp;D fans, rejoice!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;average 10, 33, 54, 70&lt;/code&gt; = 41.75&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;square root of 84&lt;/code&gt; =  9.16515138991168&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;is 765 prime&lt;/code&gt; = find whether a number is prime or not&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;random number&lt;/code&gt; = generate a random number&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;45 farenheit in celsius&lt;/code&gt; = 7.222. It works also as &lt;code&gt;45 F to C&lt;/code&gt; (shorter)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;currency-and-finance&#34;&gt;Currency and Finance&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;100 usd to eur&lt;/code&gt; = 74.28€&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;usd vs eur&lt;/code&gt; = conversion values between $ and €&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;words&#34;&gt;Words&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;0110100001100101011011000110110001101111 to ascii&lt;/code&gt; = binary to ascii conversion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;hello in binary&lt;/code&gt; = convert hello to binary. Accepts ascii, numbers and hex&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;lorem ipsum&lt;/code&gt; = generate random text&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;detect language merci&lt;/code&gt; = that&amp;rsquo;s french, of course. Works pretty well with local dialects too&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;define oxen&lt;/code&gt; = definition for oxen&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;spell incospicuous&lt;/code&gt; = check spelling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;find anagram of pretty people&lt;/code&gt; = find a possible anagram for a phrase&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;travel-1&#34;&gt;Travel&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;AZ 107&lt;/code&gt; = flight status by flight code. I found this to be somewhat unreliable but for 99% of the queries the first link is the right one&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;time in honolulu&lt;/code&gt; = what time is it in Hawaii?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;entertainment&#34;&gt;Entertainment&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;xkcd&lt;/code&gt; = get the latest xkcd comic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;cooking&#34;&gt;Cooking&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;1 tsp to gram&lt;/code&gt; = how many grams is a teaspoon?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;calories in 100 gr of cottage cheese&lt;/code&gt; = 81 calories. Works with both Imperial/Metric systems&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;carbs in rice&lt;/code&gt; = how many carbohydrates on average in a rice portion? Works also with fibers, saturated fat, magnesium etc. For more precise calculations use &lt;code&gt;how much fiber in 100gr of salmon&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;geek&#34;&gt;Geek&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;@Donearm&lt;/code&gt; = shows twitter profile&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:D&lt;/code&gt; = meaning of the :D emoticon. Not that many are supported but at least the most common are&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;password 9 strong&lt;/code&gt; = generate a random password of 9 characters&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;expand http://dlvr.it/2rwGVR&lt;/code&gt; = expand a shortened url&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;qrcode http://www.google.com&lt;/code&gt; = generate a qrcode for Google homepage&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ip address&lt;/code&gt; = show your current IP address&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;useragent&lt;/code&gt; = show your browser User-Agent&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;unicode €&lt;/code&gt; = unicode codes and name for the any symbol&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;U+123a&lt;/code&gt; = what symbol corresponds to this Unicode code?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;#33;&lt;/code&gt; = decode HTML entities&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;hex color code for dark grey&lt;/code&gt; = get RGB, HSL and CMYB values for a colour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;#368798&lt;/code&gt; = find colour from its HEX code&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;urlencode still$&lt;/code&gt; = urlencode a string (still%24 in this case). More escape codes with &lt;code&gt;url escape&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gravatar email&lt;/code&gt; = find Gravatar for an email address&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;public dns&lt;/code&gt; = list common public DNS servers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;64.200.12.10&lt;/code&gt; = IP address lookup&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ascii table&lt;/code&gt; = show the ASCII table&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;nix&#34;&gt;*nix&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;crontab 10 0 * 1 *&lt;/code&gt; = when a task is being scheduled by cron?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;unix epoch&lt;/code&gt; = time since the Unix epoch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;12343435 epoch&lt;/code&gt; = convert a Unix epoch to date. Also &lt;code&gt;unix time 12343435&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;programming&#34;&gt;Programming&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;emacs C-t&lt;/code&gt; = Emacs reference&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;html span&lt;/code&gt; = html entities reference&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;array sorting cheat sheet&lt;/code&gt; = summary of Big-O time and memory complexities for array sorting algorithms&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;css colors&lt;/code&gt; = list all named CSS colors&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;caniuse web workers&lt;/code&gt; = show browsers&amp;rsquo; support for a feature&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;various&#34;&gt;Various&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;play 2048&lt;/code&gt; = play the 2048 game directly in DuckDuckGo&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;richard gere height&lt;/code&gt; = for the curious, return the height of celebrities. Surprisingly complete for actors and musicians but lacking otherwise&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;#!Bang Syntax&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
