<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog posts on Gianluca Fiore</title>
    <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog posts on Gianluca Fiore</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 14:44:03 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pulse 15 update after one year</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/pulse-15-update-after-one-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 14:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/pulse-15-update-after-one-year/</guid>
      <description>I wrote about the Pulse 15 in my previous review. Usually I don&amp;rsquo;t review what I buy, neither here nor elsewhere, but I made an exception for this laptop as it was from a small company and geared towards Linux users. Both things I care a lot about when purchasing technology. If you are interested in purchasing it, the Pulse 15 is still available at Tuxedocomputers, you may want to head there and read that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulse 15 Review</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/pulse-15-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 14:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/pulse-15-review/</guid>
      <description>As a long time Linux user (over 20 years), the quest for a perfect Linux laptop experience has been going on for most of those years. I went through a tiny Asus EEEPc back in the mid 2000s, which served me well for the very limited purposes it could manage (the Atom processors were anything but speedy&amp;hellip;). For running Linux with a window manager and writing, browsing and listening to music it was fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fountain Pen Creator</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/fountain-pen-creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 12:54:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/fountain-pen-creator/</guid>
      <description>It’s easy to see how this blog has been neglected for a long time. My fault, obviously. Also my choice.
Point being, I’ve been barely thinking and working with my coding projects since about a year. Why? I got disillusioned. I lost interest in modern coding practices.
Let me be clear: I do like coding and I will be coding in my spare time, occasionally, forever, probably. I am going to use my coding knowledge in my future career(s) as an advantage point and to automate my work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I Know as of 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/things-i-know-as-of-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 18:11:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/things-i-know-as-of-2018/</guid>
      <description>It honestly came as a surprise a post on Overreacted by Dan Abramov. He lists all the things he doesn&amp;rsquo;t know as of 2018, in an attempt to &amp;ldquo;devalue&amp;rdquo; in the eyes of newbies any experienced developer by showing off the gaps in knowledge that usually we take for granted, expecially from those developers that work for big companies and who went through a harder interview process. Considering the number of likes and retweets the post received, I&amp;rsquo;m far from being the only one surprised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freecodecamp: There and Back Again</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/freecodecamp-there-and-back-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 15:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/freecodecamp-there-and-back-again/</guid>
      <description>Well, first of all, sorry for not updating about my progresses on Frontend development through Freecodecamp curriculum but there were basically none since last May. Why? Work got in the way, with a larger role and more duties taking over little by little the energy I had to focus on coding after work. First reason.
Second reason, health issues. I&amp;rsquo;ve been battling with the most pernicious kind of backpain since spring and it intensified around June, when it became a routine to wake up in the middle of the night due to the pain, spend half an hour trying to get back to sleep, get up much earlier than due (like 6-6:30) and spending the rest of the day in a perennial tired state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appreciation</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/appreciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 11:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/appreciation/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been surprised, even amused, by the show of affection friends show in myself. Caring about myself has never been a high priority for me, I admit, so I emotionally recoil whenever an external being cares about my wellbeing more than me. I cannot comprehend it, on an emotional level of course as logically it is natural for friends to care about each other.
What surprises me the most is the long-lasting effect I may have on people who I have barely crossed their paths during my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freecodecamp</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/freecodecamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 21:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/freecodecamp/</guid>
      <description>Frontend development was never my area. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been more of a Backend/System Administrator. I&amp;rsquo;ve never truly grokked the idea of events, DOM, making requests elsewhere and things running outside my machine, without me giving precise instruction when to run and what arguments to accept.
Yet it&amp;rsquo;s 2018 and Javascript permeates the programming world, whether we like it or not. Thus I was looking for a new challenge to keep me motivated to learn throughout the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Isn&#39;t Easy</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/programming-isnt-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 14:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/programming-isnt-easy/</guid>
      <description>I was reading, as usual, Scott Hanselman&amp;rsquo;s blog and couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more on his complaining on the recent WWDC keynote asserting that programming is easy. From his post:
 When we tell folks - kids or otherwise - that programming is easy, what will they think when it gets difficult? And it will get difficult. That&amp;rsquo;s where people find themselves saying &amp;ldquo;well, I guess I&amp;rsquo;m not wired for coding. It&amp;rsquo;s just not for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic Cocktails Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/classic-cocktails-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 11:33:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/classic-cocktails-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I&amp;rsquo;ve become the maintainer, and main contributor, of this DuckDuckGo&amp;rsquo;s Instant answer. It has been deployed on beta.duckduckgo.com only so far, as it is clearly just a beta.
My passion for cocktails and carefully mixed drinks is no mistery and thus it was only natural to write such an IA for DuckDuckGo, my main search engine since a few years. It is incomplete, I only wanted to add classic cocktails, not all, and there are a few doubts on the format of the recipes among the community (see the pull request).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back To Naples</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/backtonaples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 11:04:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/backtonaples/</guid>
      <description>Last month I went back to my hometown, Naples, for New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve. Meeting with family and showing the city to girlfriend. A very enjoyable week, I have to say, fun, drinks, good food, visiting as a tourist your old home and rejoining with 2 lovely cats at home :)
The trip reinforced my love-hate relationship with Naples. The food is outstanding, it is really, really hard to find another city with same quality food as Naples, no doubts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Guide To DuckDuckGo</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/a-brief-guide-to-duckduckgo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 14:34:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/a-brief-guide-to-duckduckgo/</guid>
      <description>Or why you should be using it even if you don&amp;rsquo;t care about privacy or don&amp;rsquo;t know what a search engine bubble may be.
It&amp;rsquo;s in no way a comprehensive guide nor &amp;ldquo;the best of&amp;rdquo; of what DuckDuckGo offers. Just what I find more useful and have been using so far.
Time  days between today and 02/28/2013 = 16 days. Unfortunately, this uses the US month/day/year format 18:30 to 19:25 = 55 minutes february calendar = print the calendar for this year&amp;rsquo;s february calendar next month = print next month&amp;rsquo;s calendar  Travel  weather = weather for your current location 80100 = search for the map of your postal code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
