<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flying on Gianluca Fiore</title>
    <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/flying/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flying on Gianluca Fiore</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:04:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/flying/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flying is terrible</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/flying-is-terrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:04:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/flying-is-terrible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never loved flying. I tolerated it in the beginning. Then grew fond of it. Until it became the worst possible way of transportation there is. Now I am considering renouncing flying altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sounded a bit dramatic, didn&amp;rsquo;t it? Oh well, imagine how strong is my frustration with flying then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Premise: I am an old flyer. I started boarding planes in the mid 1990s. Before low cost airlines, before the concept of going through an international hub to reach your final destination was born. If you wanted to fly back then, 99% of the times it was your national flag carrier airline, within Europe, and for longer flights there were alliances that meant you were sent to another national airline somewhere closer to your final destination. It was normal to have 2, max 3 flights to reach even the most remote location in the world. You flew from your local airport to a national/international hub, then to the other company&amp;rsquo;s hub, then to your final destination. Services like seat reservation, sizeable hand luggage, a simple meal, water/coffee/tea/soft drinks were all naturally included in the price of your tickets. Even in 30 minutes flight a sweet or cookie was given without costs. On some companies, beer and wine were also freely given with the cheapest ticket.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
