<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Gianluca Fiore</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/feeds/blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.gianlucafiore.it/</id><updated>2016-04-14T17:10:03+02:00</updated><entry><title>Classic Cocktails Cheat Sheet</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/classic-cocktails-cheat-sheet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-14T17:10:03+02:00</published><author><name>Gianluca Fiore</name></author><id>tag:www.gianlucafiore.it,2016-04-14:blog/classic-cocktails-cheat-sheet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I've become the maintainer, and main contributor, of &lt;a href="https://duck.co/ia/view/classic_cocktails_cheat_sheet"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; DuckDuckGo's Instant answer. It has been deployed on &lt;a href="https://beta.duckduckgo.com"&gt;beta.duckduckgo.com&lt;/a&gt; only so far, as it is clearly just a beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/cocktail_ddg.jpg" width="1024" height="765" 
alt="Classic Cocktails IA screenshot"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My passion for cocktails and carefully mixed drinks is no mistery and thus it was only natural to write such an IA for DuckDuckGo, my main search engine since a few years. It is incomplete, I only wanted to add &lt;em&gt;classic&lt;/em&gt; cocktails, not all, and there are a few doubts on the format of the recipes among the community (see the &lt;a href="https://github.com/duckduckgo/zeroclickinfo-goodies/pull/2796"&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt;). Namely, the sempiternal question about ounces, millilitres and parts. I side with the parts team but I'm writing this post also to call for anyone interested to express his/her opinions and submit new or better recipes. Any improvement or suggestion is appreciated, let's get this IA out of beta!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="duckduckgo"></category><category term="cocktail"></category><category term="drink"></category><category term="cheat sheet"></category><category term="search engine"></category></entry><entry><title>Back To Naples</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/back-to-naples.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-15T11:04:00+01:00</published><author><name>Gianluca Fiore</name></author><id>tag:www.gianlucafiore.it,2016-02-15:blog/back-to-naples.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last month I went back to my &lt;strong&gt;hometown&lt;/strong&gt;, Naples, for New Year's Eve. Meeting with family and showing the city to girlfriend. A very enjoyable week, I have to say, fun, drinks, good food, visiting as a tourist your old home and rejoining with 2 lovely cats at home :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Napoli-lungomare.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Naples"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip reinforced my &lt;strong&gt;love-hate&lt;/strong&gt; relationship with Naples. The food is &lt;strong&gt;outstanding&lt;/strong&gt;, it is really, really hard to find another city with same quality food as Naples, no doubts. People are generally warm and welcoming, open for a chat at any moment and with a hint of humanity that you don't get that often in north Italy (your mileage may vary, of course). The city is artistically rich, beautiful in a decadent way, there are still plenty of unknown to tourists places to discover, the view from Posillipo or the Vesuvio is &lt;strong&gt;breathtaking&lt;/strong&gt; and art is everywhere around you, as usual in Italy. &lt;strong&gt;Cheap&lt;/strong&gt; prices to eat out, a new, modern metro system and the best pizza in the world complete the offer of the city to visitors. It is also nearly impossible to find another city in the world which has the same quantity and quality of day trip to make: from Pompeii (and Ercolano), to Vesuvio, to Capri, Sorrento, the Amalfi coast with Positano and Caserta with its "&lt;em&gt;italian Versailles&lt;/em&gt;".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the &lt;strong&gt;love&lt;/strong&gt; part. I'd add, which is personal, memories and a lively musical background that no other city in Italy can offer. Yes, no other, only Naples has songs in neapolitan, its dialect, that are regularly sang by the best tenors/sopranos all around the world for more than a century. Everybody knows '&lt;strong&gt;O Sole Mio&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;'O Surdato Innamurato&lt;/strong&gt;. Italian music, well renowed for its melodies and good voices, was sparkled in late 19th century by Neapolitan music after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and Maradona. Which is another name for God, didn't you know? ;) (it has even a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iglesia_Maradoniana"&gt;Church&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Napoli-Maradona_altar.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="God amongst various fake idols"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then there's the &lt;strong&gt;hate&lt;/strong&gt; part, which inevitably presents itself after a few days and the "honeymoon" effect of the first moments has passed. In just a week I faced, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taximen who claimed they were making you a favour to carry you back home, in the suburbs. Get my money and shut up, please&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ice creams thrown away on the streets on a regular basis (what's wrong with a nice &lt;em&gt;gelato&lt;/em&gt; people?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;people walking in all directions, with no apparent final destination. You have to go left, and then right, and then walk in the center, randomly, just because some people have no idea where they're going to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;speaking of which, nobody has a clue how to find some monuments because there are &lt;strong&gt;no signs&lt;/strong&gt; indicating them. And good luck finding any signs that are in english...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no &lt;strong&gt;respect&lt;/strong&gt; whatsoever for normal rules on the streets. You go where you want and stop where and when you want, this is the only rule accepted by everybody in Naples. Clearly driving becomes an hellish experience as you don't have any right to pass before any other driver, you have to &lt;strong&gt;take&lt;/strong&gt; that right from the other driver or he/she'll take it from you. It's like a Sergio Leone western with cars instead of guns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;road surfaces are uneven. &lt;strong&gt;Holes&lt;/strong&gt;, access to sewage system/electrical cables/telecommunication cables/water and different kinds of pavements make it impossible to find a road that has more than half a meter &lt;strong&gt;100%&lt;/strong&gt; straight. It is amazing how it is possible to repair roads every few months and still not having a single one that is really straight. In Naples roads are repaired to fix the previous repairing, which in turn fixed an even older one. It is a never ending story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The astute reader may be thinking now that all this applies to &lt;strong&gt;other italian cities&lt;/strong&gt; too. That's true. Any big city, at least from Rome (included) to south, has the same problems as Naples, if not in some areas even worse. But none of them has been a &lt;strong&gt;splendid&lt;/strong&gt; city just a little more than 100 years ago and rapidly decayed after it was annexed to the Kingdom of Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure now many will think that &lt;strong&gt;Rome&lt;/strong&gt; has had the same destiny of Naples. Flourished for centuries until the Kingdom of Italy became a reality. &lt;strong&gt;Wrong&lt;/strong&gt;. Rome hadn't been politically and economically relevant since Charlemagne era, at least, 1200 years earlier. The only rich peoples were priests and local aristocracy, and they fuelled a lot of art, as you can see today, but normal peasants were poor, merchants didn't cross it as it was not on the sea and had nothing peculiar to offer to foreign investors. The &lt;strong&gt;Papal State&lt;/strong&gt; was also of no military importance and never grow up more than the size of 2-3 regions of nowadays Italy. As an example, &lt;strong&gt;Florence&lt;/strong&gt;, to the north, was as much as magnet for artists as Rome but its princesses married emperors and kings all around europe and it had a play in many international alliances from Middle Age till the Renaissance, if not even after. Rome has been in a decaying state since 4-500 years at least. Which is sad as it is an &lt;strong&gt;amazingly&lt;/strong&gt; beautiful city. But I digress...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naples, instead, has been important throughout its history. From Roman times, when it hosted the main &lt;strong&gt;imperial fleet&lt;/strong&gt;, was a center of Greek-Hellenistic culture and considered the capital of the best region in Italy ("Campania Felix" anyone?), through Middle Ages with the founding of the &lt;strong&gt;first public university&lt;/strong&gt; of the world in 1224, a growing population (up to &lt;strong&gt;300.000 inhabitants&lt;/strong&gt; around 16th century), and being the biggest and richest city of the biggest realm of the time, Spain, second only after its capital, Madrid. In more recent times, the richness and importance of the city was shown by the building of the &lt;strong&gt;first modern opera&lt;/strong&gt; house among the biggest italian cities, San Carlo theatre (1737, yes, before La Scala in Milan), the very &lt;strong&gt;first railway in Italy&lt;/strong&gt;, Napoli-Portici, and second in the world (1839), the &lt;strong&gt;oldest volcanology observatory&lt;/strong&gt; in the world right on the way to Vesuvio's top (1841) and being the &lt;strong&gt;biggest&lt;/strong&gt; italian city, and third in Europe after Paris and Vienna, for nearly 300 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today Naples is instead more famous for its &lt;strong&gt;dirtiness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Napoli-street.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Napoli street"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the powerful organized crime (&lt;strong&gt;Camorra&lt;/strong&gt; or "Il Sistema" as its adherent calls it), magistrally depicted in the movie and then tv series &lt;strong&gt;Gomorra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Napoli-Gomorra.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Gomorra tv series"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;commonly sneered about by northern italians, to &lt;strong&gt;racism-levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Napoli_is_not_italy.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="The always lovely Juventus football fans..."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and lack of jobs and general lower than average &lt;strong&gt;salaries&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did it happen? It goes beyond the scope of this post to explain it, countless books have been written on the history of south Italy after the reunification of Italy. Google "la questione meridionale" if you can read italian to get illuminated. What makes me suffer is that many neapolitans don't &lt;strong&gt;know&lt;/strong&gt; even half the informations I've exposed here and half of them don't feel any &lt;strong&gt;proudness&lt;/strong&gt; nor enthusiasm in being born in such a city. They suffer from a mix of &lt;strong&gt;ignorance&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;melancholia&lt;/strong&gt; and lack of &lt;strong&gt;hope&lt;/strong&gt;. It's so common to think that "Naples has always been like this" that it's astounding that the city can still produce great artists and attract big investors (latest one, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2016/01/21Apple-Opening-Europes-First-iOS-App-Development-Center-in-Italy.html"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;). It shows that among all the pain, problems and corruption, the population is inventive, smart and civil after all, at least a good slice of it. There's a strong identification between the population and the city, many neapolitans consider themselves "first neapolitan, then italian". It's a &lt;strong&gt;me-against-the-others&lt;/strong&gt; attitude, born out of feeling of having being robbed of a glorious past and given a mediocre present. From the capital of the most powerful kingdom in the italian peninsula to the third city of a republic whose powers and interests lay mostly in Rome (political) and Milan (economical). Naples was left with &lt;strong&gt;nothing&lt;/strong&gt; to be proud of in just a couple of decades after the italian reunification, not even the role of the most important harbour (that title goes to Genoa nowadays).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the first quality that comes to mind about Naples is having the best &lt;strong&gt;pizza&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Napoli-pizza.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Pizza neapolitan style"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very little for a city with such a long and prominent past. It is of no surprise then that neapolitans have such a strong feeling of revenge against the North italians who "stole our money", "sneer at us" and "emarginate us". That feeling was embodied in sport, when the greatest footballer of all times, &lt;strong&gt;Diego Armando Maradona&lt;/strong&gt;, led Napoli football team to win the italian league twice against the "evil" powers of the north, Juventus, Inter and Milan. It had never happened before for a team south of Rome to win the league and that event back in the '80s was and still is the most dear in the minds of every neapolitan. If Naples couldn't compete anymore as a political entity, in the industries or in commerce, at least it could in football. Years of shaming and discomfort were fuelled in the victories on the pitch and the main author of them was raised to &lt;strong&gt;God-like&lt;/strong&gt; levels by the local population. It was a &lt;em&gt;"si, se puede!"&lt;/em&gt; moment for the entire city, which though quickly returned to normality after Maradona left the club. Ephemeral, fleeting, transitory. Sure. But &lt;strong&gt;powerful&lt;/strong&gt;, very powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what pains me the most. That neapolitans could summon so much joy and enthusiasm for sport successes but can't to make the city better. We can fight &lt;strong&gt;against&lt;/strong&gt; something, to be better than somebody who we feel has mistreated us, but we can't fight for &lt;strong&gt;ourselves&lt;/strong&gt;, to improve our standard of living. This we'd need to learn to be back where we were. We lost the capacity to believe that just ourselves can make our future great, without waiting for help from the central government or saints. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"Se Dio vuole"&lt;/em&gt; is a very common phrase to be heard in Naples. It means, "if God wants". At which I always reply: &lt;em&gt;"why shouldn't he want?"&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photos courtesy: &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/manfrys/13896608865/"&gt;Napoli Lungomare&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/131948873@N07/19170987655/"&gt;Napoli Street&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/95268887@N00/263753643/"&gt;Pizza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="naples"></category><category term="napoli"></category><category term="italy"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="life"></category></entry><entry><title>terminalCV</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/terminalcv.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-05T11:44:00+02:00</published><author><name>Gianluca Fiore</name></author><id>tag:www.gianlucafiore.it,2015-10-05:blog/terminalcv.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This goes into the "software I'm going to hack on" category. As the &lt;a href="https://github.com/hauckd"&gt;author&lt;/a&gt; says, terminalCV is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;A command line CV for sysadmins
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The due screenshot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/terminalcv.jpg" width="662" height="823" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To see it in action click on the new link on the sidebar, &lt;strong&gt;TerminalCV&lt;/strong&gt;. Being a lover of all things CLI, I found terminalCV a great idea, not just for sysadmins but for developers in general (altough you can reason that for developers there's already Github). I'm planning to add a few features to it, like non-programming skills, and themeing (which I suck at usually but it's just a CLI so it's not that complicated :) ).&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="terminal"></category><category term="cli"></category><category term="cv"></category><category term="programming"></category></entry><entry><title>First Months In Poland</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/first-months-in-poland.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-15T17:33:00+02:00</published><author><name>Gianluca Fiore</name></author><id>tag:www.gianlucafiore.it,2015-09-15:blog/first-months-in-poland.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/sky-blue-flag-poland.jpg" width="1024" height="765" 
alt="Poland Flag"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may, or probably may not, know, I've moved to &lt;strong&gt;Poland&lt;/strong&gt; last April.
Don't bother asking why as I'm still looking for an answer to.
There are a few good reasons, which I'm sure the male readers will have
already come up with, but it was mostly an instinctive decision. And I'm 
not regretting it so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are quite a few &lt;strong&gt;differences&lt;/strong&gt; between living in Poland and in my 
home country, Italy. Besides the obvious different climate, there are 
some totally unexpected or not exactly what I expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;: these are just my experiences. I claim not to have a perfect 
nor complete understanding of Polish customs and society. Take 
everything following with a pinch of salt (or, better, two).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Poles drink. A lot&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/toolmantim/6371671547" title="
Vodka Lineup"&gt;&lt;img 
src="https://farm7.staticflickr.com/6094/6371671547_f32442c97c_b.jpg" 
width="1024" height="765" alt="Vodka Lineup"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async 
src="//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" 
charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poland is 
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_alcohol_consumption_per_capita"&gt;13th&lt;/a&gt; 
on the list of annual alcohol consumption per capita. Not surprising at 
all. But if you actually come here you will realize the why: alcohol is 
everywhere. You need a bottle of whisky at 03:00? No problem, hit up one 
of the thousands of &lt;strong&gt;Alkohole 24h&lt;/strong&gt; shops all around Poland and you will 
find everything from whisky to beer to wine to soft drinks to make 
cocktails with your favourite spirit. Or, are you driving and forgot to 
bring along the beer? &lt;em&gt;Nie ma problemu&lt;/em&gt;, there's alcohol at most gas 
stations too! I've been told there was in discussion a law to prohibit 
selling alcohol in those places but it caused so much outrage that the 
proposal was taken back. Seeing a lone driver buying 6 cans of beer for 
a 1 hour drive on a highway isn't uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main thing is, even if most Poles don't like to admit that they drink 
much, &lt;strong&gt;they do&lt;/strong&gt;. All of them. Young and old. I can't count how many old 
ladies I found buying spirits at the nearby supermarket. Old in their 
sixties. And I mean spirits, not just wine and beer. They go straight to 
the strong stuff. Yet I didn't see more drunkards on the streets. No more 
than London or Paris. Not even on Saturday nights there are many scenes 
of girls throwing up in the middle of the streets or guys being 
obnoxious after too many drinks. Despite drinking a lot, they have quite 
an high tolerance to alcohol (to the dismay of many foreigner men 
thinking of having an easy time with the girls...). This makes for 
alcoholism being a &lt;strong&gt;lesser problem&lt;/strong&gt; than you'd expect considering the 
sheer amount of alcohol being ingested by the local population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet it is seen as a huge problem by the politicians: everywhere along 
the "no smoking allowed" signs there are also "no alcohol allowed" 
signs. Even where you wouldn't expect, like buses or public restrooms.
Drinking is just part of their &lt;strong&gt;culture&lt;/strong&gt;, it is not unusual to be stopped
on the streets by poor people asking for 2-3 złoty "for vodka". 
Especially if you look rich or foreigner. They don't bother you much, 
just saying no is enough to stop them asking. And I appreciate the 
honesty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;There are no rules regarding eating&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an italian, I'm used to have breakfast, lunch around &lt;strong&gt;12:00-14:00&lt;/strong&gt;, 
maybe aperitif around &lt;strong&gt;17:00-19:00&lt;/strong&gt; and dinner at &lt;strong&gt;19:00-21:00&lt;/strong&gt;. Some 
exceptions can be done because of work, obviously, but those are the 
general times we eat. Conscious exceptions are frowned upon or 
considered weird. And we have a very strict etiquette about food, like 
salads come after the main dish, you don't eat bread with pasta, no 
cappuccino after 12:00 (looking at you 'mericans...), spirits/liqueurs 
are to be drank at the end of the meal etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poles &lt;strong&gt;don't give a shit&lt;/strong&gt; about those rules. The only meal you can be sure 
they have is breakfast: at &lt;strong&gt;home&lt;/strong&gt;. Hardly any Poles have breakfast at a 
bar. The most they do is grabbing a coffee on the go but they have 
already eaten something before leaving home. Which is way more healthy 
btw and I hope the hordes of Starbucks, Costa Coffe, KFC and such won't 
change it ever. This is a custom that I'd like everybody to follow, 
actually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lunch? They call it &lt;em&gt;obiad&lt;/em&gt; and is anywhere between &lt;strong&gt;12:00&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;17:00&lt;/strong&gt;. Which 
means it gets mixed with "supper", usually from &lt;strong&gt;17:00 till 22:00&lt;/strong&gt;. 
Or, more commonly, anytime they have a moment to eat. Ah, don't call it 
dinner as that means also &lt;em&gt;obiad&lt;/em&gt;, but use &lt;em&gt;kolacja&lt;/em&gt;, which is awfully 
close to the italian &lt;em&gt;colazione&lt;/em&gt;, breakfast, to my utter confusion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, just eat when you want and you'll be fine in Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rules&lt;/strong&gt; at the table? Nothing of this sort. I've seen everything, from ice 
cubes being added to wine (&lt;em&gt;"it's not cold enough!"&lt;/em&gt;), to the omnipresent 
cappuccino along with pasta, to cooking pasta with a broth cube (!), to 
eating salad, then soup, then cake, then fruits and then potatoes, to 
eating salad along with pasta/pizza/soup because "we Poles like to mix 
things up". Even ordering a pint of beer &lt;strong&gt;together with&lt;/strong&gt; a glass of 
vodka and happily sipping either, alternatively. The italian in me dies 
a little bit whenever I see something along those lines. I will have to 
become Polish very soon or risk dying altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Food quality isn't great&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I'm spoiled by &lt;strong&gt;growing up&lt;/strong&gt; in Italy but I am having an hard time 
finding a supermarket that sells good quality food. Especially fruits, 
seafood and meat. I had expected before coming here to have good meat at 
least as polish cuisine is heavily meat-based but no, it's hard to find 
any cut that is not nearly tasteless, often even the most expensive ones 
are bland in flavours. And I'm used to tens of different cuts, even at 
supermarkets. Here it seems they use the same 6-7 cuts for cooking every 
meat dish, which is &lt;strong&gt;baffling&lt;/strong&gt;.  Cheeses are fine, albeit most are 
imported. Try the &lt;strong&gt;Lithuanian cheeses&lt;/strong&gt;. Vegetables are ok, fruits is not 
but for the delicious apples (but I don't like them so I'm screwed). I 
have no idea why a banana becomes dark in 2 days here when in Italy 
takes 4-5 days (and it's hotter there too). They also suffer from the 
same problem of Germany: they have tens of different kinds of bread but 
&lt;strong&gt;no clue&lt;/strong&gt; how to bake it. I'd kill for a slice of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pane_di_Altamura"&gt;Altamura 
Bread&lt;/a&gt;. Here are the 
usual dark, rye, bread-with-some-nuts-or-seeds in/on kind of breads that 
dominate the market. For really good baked bread you have to go up in 
the ladder of quality (and cost).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Butter and margarina are aplenty and good. Olive oil is expensive, as 
you could expect. They sell &lt;strong&gt;enormously-sized yeast&lt;/strong&gt;, 75-100g, which I 
wonder still what they use it for as the most they bake are Pierogi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kitchenwench/3254936910/" 
title="Strawberry and Farmer&amp;#x27;s Cheese Pierogis"&gt;&lt;img 
src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3098/3254936910_8de497156b_o.jpg" 
width="1024" height="765" alt="Strawberry and Farmer&amp;#x27;s Cheese 
Pierogis"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pizza can be surprisingly good, I know a couple of places where it is 
&lt;strong&gt;really good&lt;/strong&gt;. No, they aren't even run by italian, real polish pizzerias. 
Fish is nowhere to be seen, especially at restaurants. In supermarkets 
is always frozen and imported but for salmon and sardines. Generally, 
avoid it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Foreigners are still weird&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poles aren't used to meet foreigners. Being on the other side of the 
&lt;strong&gt;Iron Curtain&lt;/strong&gt; for nearly half a century and immediately after 2 decades of 
&lt;strong&gt;emigration&lt;/strong&gt; has made Poland one of the countries with the &lt;strong&gt;fewest&lt;/strong&gt; number of 
immigrants in EU. Something along the lines of 700.000 foreigners among 
38 millions of Poles. If you take into account that most of those are 
Ukrainian immigrants, who visually are very close to Poles, being a 
mediterranean-looking guy means I am looked at with a mix of curiosity 
(most of the time), interest (sometime), aversity (more than seems sane 
to), hate (a couple of times). I stand out very clearly among the local 
population, it's impossible for me to pass as a Polish citizen of Polish 
ancestry (only for a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polska_Roma"&gt;Polska 
Roma&lt;/a&gt; maybe).
While this can have its advantages (&lt;em&gt;"hey look, an italian guy!"&lt;/em&gt;), it's 
very &lt;strong&gt;unsettling&lt;/strong&gt; at times to be looked at by men and women of all ages 
just because they seem to never or very rarely having seen a 
dark-skinned man. It never happened to me anywhere else in the world, 
not even as a white man in Dominican Republic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, despite my different look, Poles are so little used to meet 
foreigners that 99,9% of the time I'm &lt;strong&gt;first addressed in Polish&lt;/strong&gt; and only 
after they realize I don't understand, in English. Even in touristic places 
like the Palac Kultury i Nauki, where they'd expect to see many 
foreigner tourists, I was first addressed in Polish. Sometimes I wonder 
if it's more not being used to foreigners or not being able to conceive 
why somebody who is not polish would come to live in Poland. I've been 
asked many times why I chose Poland over Italy and so far I couldn't 
come with a definite, credible answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shows also how many Poles consider their country ugly and/or 
uninteresting. Which I disagree with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Communist Blocks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/photobeppus/8300737041/" 
title="Warszawa"&gt;&lt;img 
src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8215/8300737041_544d562c5e_b.jpg" 
width="1024" height="768" alt="Warszawa"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async 
src="//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" 
charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They're &lt;strong&gt;everywhere&lt;/strong&gt;. Nearly all Polish cities were mostly or totally 
destroyed during WWII and the communist governments following it had to 
rebuild a lot of lost housing. They followed the example of Soviet 
Russia and built those enormous, grey, squared-windows blocks 
everywhere, in every city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's face it, they are &lt;strong&gt;not pretty&lt;/strong&gt;. And Poles know it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, they aren't as bad looking as some examples of western 
architecture that you can see in the peripheries of Madrid, Rome or San 
Francisco. They have a bad reputation for being "the ugliest ones" but 
it's not rightfully earned, there are &lt;strong&gt;worst buildings&lt;/strong&gt; in the so called 
"first world" countries. Only they may look uglier because they are much 
bigger (some have like 4 stairwells and 8 different entrances for the 
same building) and really everywhere. Put a single ugly building in a 
pretty city and it will look like a mistake; put tens of ugly buildings 
in a single city and the whole city will look bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, they are extremely &lt;strong&gt;functionals&lt;/strong&gt;. Communists apparently hated lifts so 
most of them which are less than 6-7 floors have none. Some have 
installed one after the coming of democracy. So no lifts for shorter 
buildings. But the stairs are &lt;strong&gt;large&lt;/strong&gt;. The steps aren't too tall or too 
narrow. I bet some russian architect made a research on this and found 
the precise size they should be. My 42 EU size feet fits perfectly. 
Amazing. Main building door is 99% of the time activated by an 
electronic system where you press the number of your apartment, the key 
button and a 4 digit code to open the door. Alternatively, there's the 
key. It's a bit like in Ukraine but over there is still mechanical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the rooms inside are &lt;strong&gt;warm&lt;/strong&gt;. Very. The external walls are thick while 
the walls separating two apartments are not, which helps to keep the 
cold away and sharing the heating warmness from apartment to adjacent 
apartment (and also hearing the discussions of your neighbours). Every 
building has a &lt;strong&gt;basement&lt;/strong&gt;, including new ones, where you can store some of your 
stuff, included in the rent. Also most if not all have a stair to access 
the roof which Poles don't use it at all as I haven't seen anybody on 
any roof in 5 months of staying (and it was during summer). A large part 
of all buildings have room to park the car/bike in front or on the back 
of them, many green areas around and occasionally a &lt;strong&gt;recreational 
area&lt;/strong&gt; with basketball court, ping pong table and entertainment area for 
children. Speaking of which, I've seen toys inside bank offices, in 
every airport and even in a few big shops. They do care about the 
children (but they don't make 
&lt;a href="http://www.indexmundi.com/facts/poland/birth-rate"&gt;many anymore&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Beds&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bed is a bed. &lt;strong&gt;This is a bed&lt;/strong&gt; (as the wise cat clearly agrees):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/koldre/544234299" title="Ikea Mandal 
Bed"&gt;&lt;img 
src="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1154/544234299_dcfc309eb5_b.jpg" 
width="819" height="1024" alt="Ikea Mandal Bed"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async 
src="//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" 
charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anything else isn't&lt;/strong&gt;. In Poland they often try to sell you a &lt;strong&gt;sofa-bed&lt;/strong&gt; for 
a bed. It is not, dear Polish friends; it's just a sofa that can be 
opened and you can sleep on. That doesn't make it a bed as much as being 
able to sleep on an airplane seat make it a proper bed. Understood?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Language&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every foreigner here has to face it on a day to day basis: &lt;strong&gt;Polish is 
hard&lt;/strong&gt;. And every foreigner complains about it. And every Poles understand 
it's impossible to master it in less than &lt;strong&gt;1 year&lt;/strong&gt;. Or &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I don't think it needs so long at all. 1 year is a good 
guess for most, intelligent, people. 2 only if you don't give studying 
Polish much time or are very bad at languages in general. The worst part 
are the many &lt;strong&gt;declension cases&lt;/strong&gt; (which was expected) and the &lt;strong&gt;pronunciation&lt;/strong&gt; 
(which was not): one dipthong like &lt;em&gt;"rz"&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;"sz"&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;"cz"&lt;/em&gt;, or difficult sounds 
like &lt;em&gt;"ł"&lt;/em&gt; are easy enough to pronounce (and they don't change according 
to the position!), but when more than 1 is present in a single word my 
brain spins. Try to pronounce words like &lt;strong&gt;"Szczebrzeszynie"&lt;/strong&gt; or 
&lt;strong&gt;"chrząszcz"&lt;/strong&gt; (but have first at hand the number of your otolaryngologist 
for when your tongue gets stuck).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So get ready to use &lt;em&gt;"nie mowie po polsku"&lt;/em&gt; (I don't speak Polish) very 
often and take aside 1 hour each day to study Polish if you are serious 
about staying in Poland. Which it is supposed to be your duty as a 
modern, globalized citizen of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I know most won't care, so &lt;strong&gt;English will be your anchor&lt;/strong&gt;. Luckily for 
them, 90% of the younger generations, &amp;lt;30yo, know basic to average 
english. Some have really amazing english levels. Yet it's not 
Netherlands or Scandinavia, as soon as you are outside of the most 
touristic areas even speaking with 20yo people will become hard if not 
totally impossible. There's a huge &lt;strong&gt;gap&lt;/strong&gt; between well educated people and 
those who have average or lower than average education: the english of 
the latter will be at most basic, if not that bad that they could as 
well speak polish. If you consider that many 40+ well educated people 
&lt;strong&gt;didn't study english at school&lt;/strong&gt; at all (because, Russians!), you can 
imagine how small is the population range that a foreigner can have a 
normal discussion in english. The situation is clearly improving, in 20 
years you could live here like you can now in Scandinavia, without any 
knowledge of the local language, but for now be warned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Traffic is amazingly low&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure all my polish friends will cry in &lt;strong&gt;outrage&lt;/strong&gt; at this but trust me, 
it's nowhere near what it's like to drive in Rome or Naples. That's hell 
on earth compared to Warsaw. There's a reason why we say&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;if you can drive in Naples, you can drive everywhere
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;and it's not because of the very strict driving schools. Seriously, 
traffic is mostly smooth but for a couple of spots at the usual rush 
hours. Finding a parking spot for your car is unbelievably easier than 
back in Italy: in Warsaw's centre, in front of the Palace of Justice, 
you can be sure to find an empty spot at every hour. Nothing of this 
sort can be said for any major italian city; if I had found one like 
that I would consider it &lt;strong&gt;my lucky day&lt;/strong&gt;. Here it seems normal to have a 
few empty spots here and there even in the very centre of the city on a 
weekday morning. I guess because most poles don't have a car (due to 
poverty or choice) and rely on the, mostly &lt;strong&gt;excellent&lt;/strong&gt;, public 
transportation and bike lanes systems. Admittedly, I don't feel the 
need to buy a car anytime soon either. Streets are also very wide and 
there's room to park cars everywhere. But don't try to park your car too 
close to a turn, it will get &lt;strong&gt;confiscated&lt;/strong&gt; in a nanosecond and you will be 
frowned upon by any bystander. I saw it myself and it wasn't nice for 
the driver, as much as it wasn't for the driver who got invested by a 
tram because he didn't clear up the path for it and was also &lt;strong&gt;fined&lt;/strong&gt; 
for interrupting public transportation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trams are &lt;strong&gt;evil&lt;/strong&gt; here, don't mess with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Weather&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talk about the weather last, contrarily to most foreigners (trying to 
be original, see?). I have not yet experienced the &lt;strong&gt;cold polish 
winter&lt;/strong&gt; but for a brief stint last year when I made a supervising trip 
of 5 days. That was enough to give me a good idea though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, it is &lt;strong&gt;cold&lt;/strong&gt;. Grey too. And extremely &lt;strong&gt;windy&lt;/strong&gt;, which is the worst thing 
you can face when on a 50m wide and 2km long street without any covering 
but for leafeless trees. Try to cross a bridge over the Vistula in the 
middle of the winter and I'm sure you will be ready to be sold as frozen 
meat before you reach the other end. &lt;strong&gt;Nobody&lt;/strong&gt; crosses a bridge here in 
winter. Nobody that plans to survive, at least. Often walking out feels 
like a race from a heated place to the next with the prize being 
survival. Once I took the road from the Stadion Narodowy (the football 
stadium) north towards the Praga neighborhood along the river because I 
got off the tram one stop earlier than I intended: &lt;strong&gt;worst decision ever&lt;/strong&gt;. 
It was like 1km or even less but I felt like the poor Athenian soldier 
running back to Athens after Marathon battle. Only with harsh cold and 
strong wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet is getting &lt;strong&gt;better&lt;/strong&gt;. Last winter was below -10°C only for a couple of 
weeks, most of the time was between 0 and -10, which is mild here. 
Spring has been pretty ok and sunny and this summer has been universally 
considered as one of the warmest ever. It felt like Italy a handful of 
days. We have hope this winter won't be that bad after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it won't, luckily, as I said above, houses are usually very warm. 
Restaurant and bars even more as they put the heating system to the 
maximum out of sheer &lt;strong&gt;hate of winter&lt;/strong&gt;, there's no other possible 
explanation: it is normal to stay in t-shirts inside and then having to 
put 3 layers on before going out. Perfect to get a cold. Which 
considering the &lt;strong&gt;abnormal&lt;/strong&gt; number of pharmacies available seems to be 
quite common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all I'm &lt;strong&gt;enjoying&lt;/strong&gt; my staying in Poland. People are generally very 
nice, educated and respectful. Honest too. The problems I have told of 
above aren't that bad, nothing that would make me decide to go back to 
Italy. Poland at least is improving its shortcomings, Italy has been 
&lt;strong&gt;stagnating&lt;/strong&gt; for decades. Unfortunately, not just the economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S.=for any criticism, correction or outraged messages, feel free to 
mail, comment or @'s me on Twitter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photos courtesy: &lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/flag-of-poland-5611/"&gt;Poland 
Flag&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/toolmantim"&gt;Vodka&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kitchenwench"&gt;Pierogi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/photobeppus"&gt;Communist 
Blocks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/koldre"&gt;Bed and 
Cat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="poland"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="moving out"></category><category term="experience"></category></entry><entry><title>A Brief Guide To DuckDuckGo</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/a-brief-guide-to-duckduckgo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-09T09:16:48+02:00</published><author><name>Gianluca Fiore</name></author><id>tag:www.gianlucafiore.it,2015-06-09:blog/a-brief-guide-to-duckduckgo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Or why you should be using it even if you don't care about &lt;a href="http://donttrack.us/"&gt;privacy&lt;/a&gt; or don't know what a &lt;a href="http://dontbubble.us/"&gt;search engine bubble&lt;/a&gt; may be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's in no way comprehensive nor "the best of". Just what I find more useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;days between today and 02/28/2013&lt;/code&gt; = 16 days. Unfortunately, this uses the US month/day/year format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;18:30 to 19:25&lt;/code&gt; = 55 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;february calendar&lt;/code&gt; = print the calendar for this year's february&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Travel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weather&lt;/code&gt; = weather for your current location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;80100&lt;/code&gt; = search for the map of your postal code. Finds also matching codes in other countries. Or you can specify &lt;code&gt;80100 Germany&lt;/code&gt; to  get the result you want straight away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;florence sunrise&lt;/code&gt; = when does the sun rises in Florence? Here too it works with in the local language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;temp in new york&lt;/code&gt; = current temperature in New York&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Numbers and Math&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;uuid&lt;/code&gt; = generate a random unique identifier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;roman numeral MCCXXII&lt;/code&gt; = convert the roman numeral in arabic. That's 1222, btw&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;md5 whatever&lt;/code&gt; = calculate md5 sum of &lt;code&gt;whatever&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sha whatever&lt;/code&gt; = calculate sha sum of &lt;code&gt;whatever&lt;/code&gt;. Works with &lt;code&gt;sha256&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;sha512&lt;/code&gt; too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;goog&lt;/code&gt; = company and stock data (Google)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;roll 4d12&lt;/code&gt; = simulate rolling 4 d12 dices. D&amp;amp;D fans, rejoice!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;average 10, 33, 54, 70&lt;/code&gt; = 41.75&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;square root of 84&lt;/code&gt; =  9.16515138991168&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;is 765 prime&lt;/code&gt; = find whether a number is prime or not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;random number&lt;/code&gt; = generate a random number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;45 farenheit in celsius&lt;/code&gt; = 7.222. It works also as &lt;code&gt;45 F to C&lt;/code&gt; (shorter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Currency and Finance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;100 usd to eur&lt;/code&gt; = 74.28€&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;usd vs eur&lt;/code&gt; = conversion values between $ and €&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Words&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;0110100001100101011011000110110001101111 to ascii&lt;/code&gt; = binary to ascii conversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;hello in binary&lt;/code&gt; = convert hello to binary. Accepts ascii, numbers and hex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;anagram the ship was sailing&lt;/code&gt; = anagram a phrase. Works in any language but results are rarely meaningful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;lorem ipsum&lt;/code&gt; = generate random text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;detect language merci&lt;/code&gt; = that's french, of course. Works pretty well with local dialects too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;define oxen&lt;/code&gt; = definition for oxen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;spell incospicuous&lt;/code&gt; = check spelling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;random word&lt;/code&gt; = generate a random, english, word. It's possible to specify the range of characters length with &lt;code&gt;random word 5-9&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;chars little test&lt;/code&gt; = how many characters in &lt;code&gt;little test&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;related to cat&lt;/code&gt; = words related to &lt;code&gt;cat&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;synonyms for cat&lt;/code&gt; = find synonyms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Travel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;AZ 107&lt;/code&gt; = flight status by flight code. I found this to be somewhat unreliable but 99% of the queries the first link is the right one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;distance paris to london&lt;/code&gt; = 342km. Works in the local language too (Koln instead of Cologne, Roma instead of Rome etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;time in honolulu&lt;/code&gt; = what time is it in Hawaii?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Entertainment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;monumension album by Enslaved&lt;/code&gt; = info on an album&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Jesus Saves, I Spend song by St. Vincent&lt;/code&gt; = info on a song&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;songs by Metallica&lt;/code&gt; = most popular songs on Last.fm from Metallica&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;imdb Young Frankenstein&lt;/code&gt; = info on a movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;xkcd&lt;/code&gt; = get the latest xkcd comic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cooking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;1 tsp to gram&lt;/code&gt; = how many grams is a teaspoon?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;calories in 100 gr of cottage cheese&lt;/code&gt; = 81 calories. Works with both Imperial/Metric systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;carbs in rice&lt;/code&gt; = how many carbohydrates on average in a rice portion? Works also with fibers, saturated fat, magnesium etc. For more precise calculations use &lt;code&gt;how much fiber in 100gr of salmon&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;nutrition in a kiwi&lt;/code&gt; = detailed nutritional facts about Kiwis. The fruit, that is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;how to mix a Americano&lt;/code&gt; = how to prepare an Americano?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Geek&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;@Donearm&lt;/code&gt; = shows twitter profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;#duckduckgo&lt;/code&gt; = Twitter hashtag search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;google+ Gianluca Fiore&lt;/code&gt; = search for G+ profiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:D&lt;/code&gt; = meaning of the :D emoticon. Not that many are supported but at least the most common are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;password 9 strong&lt;/code&gt; = generate a random password of 9 characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;expand http://dlvr.it/2rwGVR&lt;/code&gt; = expand a shortened url&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;qrcode http://www.google.com&lt;/code&gt; = generate a qrcode for Google homepage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;is duckduckgo.com up?&lt;/code&gt; = is our favourite duck up?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ip address&lt;/code&gt; = show your current IP address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;useragent&lt;/code&gt; = show your browser User-Agent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;unicode €&lt;/code&gt; = unicode codes and name for the any symbol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;U+123a&lt;/code&gt; = what symbol corresponds to this Unicode code?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;#33;&lt;/code&gt; = decode HTML entities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;reddit luajit&lt;/code&gt; = search Reddit posts about LuaJit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;port 23&lt;/code&gt; = TCP port information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;hex color code for dark grey&lt;/code&gt; = get RGB, HSL and CMYB values for a colour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;#368798&lt;/code&gt; = find colour from its HEX code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;urlencode still$&lt;/code&gt; = urlencode a string (still%24 in this case). More escape codes with &lt;code&gt;url escape&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bitly url&lt;/code&gt; = shortens url with bit.ly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gravatar email&lt;/code&gt; = find Gravatar for an email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;public dns&lt;/code&gt; = list common public DNS servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;64.200.12.10&lt;/code&gt; = IP address lookup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;*nix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;man ctags&lt;/code&gt; = manpage for ctags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;crontab 10 0 * 1 *&lt;/code&gt; = when a task is being scheduled by cron?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;epoch&lt;/code&gt; = time since the Unix epoch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;12343435 time&lt;/code&gt; = convert a Unix epoch to date. Also &lt;code&gt;unix time 12343435&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Programming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;http status 102&lt;/code&gt; = reference for http status codes. More generally, it accepts various query for many languages. For example, &lt;code&gt;lua function&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;c #define&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;python urllib2&lt;/code&gt; all return, more or less, what you'd expect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;emacs C-t&lt;/code&gt; = Emacs reference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;html span&lt;/code&gt; = html entities reference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git cherry-pick&lt;/code&gt; = git manpage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;lua jobs&lt;/code&gt; = Github Jobs search (only 1 for lua, me sad...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;!Bang Syntax&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are a bit different since they don't make queries on DuckDuckGo but use other websites to search &lt;em&gt;into&lt;/em&gt;. In general, it's like using &lt;code&gt;site:http://www.mysite.com query&lt;/code&gt;, only with far less keystrokes.&lt;br /&gt;
There are a whole bunch of them. Like, &lt;a href="https://duckduckgo.com/bang.html"&gt;a lot&lt;/a&gt;. Do browse that list, I'm sure there are many sites that you use to browse to in order to make a search with their internal search form but with these you can do it directly from DuckDuckGo main page. Extremely handy when you already know where to look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourites are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!tumblr&lt;/code&gt; = search on Tumblr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!h33t&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;!torrent&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;!torrentz&lt;/code&gt; = torrent search. You know, legal stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!firefox&lt;/code&gt; = search Firefox add-ons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!vim&lt;/code&gt; = search on vim.org. I use it all the time to know what a new plugin does&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!appbrain&lt;/code&gt; = Android app search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!gist&lt;/code&gt; = Gists search. Some great gems can be found among gists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!github&lt;/code&gt; = repository search on Github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!python&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;!python3&lt;/code&gt; = search in Python (2 or 3) documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!xdaf&lt;/code&gt; = xda-developers.com forum search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!so&lt;/code&gt; = Stackoverflow. Best way to get a quick answer to a programming problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!unix&lt;/code&gt; = search in *nix source code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!distro&lt;/code&gt; = lookup a Linux distribution on distrowatch.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!archlinux&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;!archwiki&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;!aur&lt;/code&gt; = search, respectively, on Archlinux forum, wiki and among AUR packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!amit&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;!amuk&lt;/code&gt; = Amazon search (It and Uk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!cstheory&lt;/code&gt; = computer science questions and answers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!lonelyplanet&lt;/code&gt; = Lonely Planet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!tripadvisor&lt;/code&gt; = TripAdvisor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!bmaps&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;!map&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;!osm&lt;/code&gt; = Map searches (Bing, Google and OpenStreet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!urban&lt;/code&gt; = slang words search on Urban Dictionary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!allmusic&lt;/code&gt; = Allmusic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!define&lt;/code&gt; = Define a word&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!spanishdict&lt;/code&gt; = From spanish to english&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="search engine"></category><category term="duckduckgo"></category><category term="guide"></category></entry></feed>