<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Gianluca Fiore - blog</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/feeds/blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.gianlucafiore.it/</id><updated>2016-11-26T11:44:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Fidel Castro (1926-2016)</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/fidel-castro-1926-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-26T11:44:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-11-26T11:44:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Gianluca Fiore</name></author><id>tag:www.gianlucafiore.it,2016-11-26:/blog/fidel-castro-1926-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was a shock to hear about Fidel Castro's death this morning. Not because it was unexpected, 90 years old and with a deadly cancer, but because he over time had become the Lemmy Kilmister of international politic: always true to himself and his values, dressing nearly in the same …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was a shock to hear about Fidel Castro's death this morning. Not because it was unexpected, 90 years old and with a deadly cancer, but because he over time had become the Lemmy Kilmister of international politic: always true to himself and his values, dressing nearly in the same ways for years (but for those dreadful Adidas tracksuits) and considered immortal. Both died in less than 12 months, both due to cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to write an &lt;strong&gt;eulogy&lt;/strong&gt; nor a &lt;strong&gt;critic&lt;/strong&gt; of Fidel Castro. It is not my job and more knowledgeable people have done it. Nor it would change how you see him; he was such a polarizing figure that most will either consider him a ruthless tyrant or a iconic revolutionary. He was probably both but people from both camps usually ignore his other side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. What I'm going to write is about how skewed is our perception of international politics, at least in the Nato-member countries. How much of it is skewed on the side of the USA that we barely think there can be a different point of view. Or if we do, we don't understand it. Most of the life of Fidel Castro was shaped by his opposition to the USA so it seems fitting to discuss of this now, on the day of his death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me answer as soon as possible what most detractors of him are thinking right now: &lt;strong&gt;Castro killed thousands of opposers&lt;/strong&gt;. Many more had to flee across the sea to find refuge in Florida to escape certain death. These acts don't put Castro in a much different camp than Stalin, Mao Zedong, Pol Pot or any other socialist/communist leaders. Unfortunately such ideology, like nazi/fascism, is associated with blood-thirsty dictators who repress freedom to keep their powers throughout history, to the point that we don't even consider the chance that there could be a moderate communist president. Moderate here is to be taken as "not ruthlessly killing any opposer and repressing freedom of speech". Some examples may be the late Gorbachev, Allende and a score of socialist/communist parties throughout the world who at times shared the power with other, less leftist ones, and which never killed anybody. Sweden may also be seen as a country ruled for decades by a government with strong socialist tendencies, and with great results, economically and socially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the main thing to be taken here is: while it is possible to have a communist/socialist government that is also not a complete dictatorship, why every crime of it is blamed to the ideology and not on the person in charge? The same happens with nazi-fascism: Hitler, Mussolini, Pinochet are considered "bad" &lt;strong&gt;because&lt;/strong&gt; of their ideology, more than because of their person. Everybody will agree that Stalin was more ruthless and a tyrant than Lenin, despite sharing the same ideology. Yet Lenin isn't exactly thought of a positive figure because he was a communist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why don't we also blame capitalism for the bad guy of the moment? There have been countless examples of people being killed, enslaved, sent to prison for purely economical reasons. Capitalistic reasons, so to say. Think about &lt;strong&gt;colonialism&lt;/strong&gt; in Africa and the post-colonialist rulers (Google for Yakubu Gowon, for instance). Entire &lt;strong&gt;genocides&lt;/strong&gt; were started just to exploit natural resources or land. Ask the Native Americans, or the Congo people under belgian rule, the &lt;a href="http://www.smithsonianmag.com/history/brutal-genocide-colonial-africa-finally-gets-its-deserved-recognition-180957073/"&gt;South-West Africa genocide under the Germans&lt;/a&gt;, Apartheid in South Africa, the aboriginal people treatment by the Australian government and the systematic destruction of the indigenous culture throughout Latin America. And these are just a few examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's easy to retort that these crimes could have happened also due to communism or the king/prime minister in charge at the time was totally to blame. While this could have been true if we were talking of a single episode under the rule of a single person, most of those examples are spanning decades if not centuries, under many different rulers and cultures. And it's not even to blame "white people", as modern revisionists would like to: Assyrians, surely not white, were known for deporting entire tribes who rebelled against their rule already 3000 years ago. The Mongols killed millions of people back in the Middle Ages, exclusively for the need of more land. More recently, the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Armenian_Genocide"&gt;Armenian Genocide&lt;/a&gt; comes to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, the only thing all those crimes have in common, unlike crimes committed by communist/socialist leaders, is the desire to &lt;strong&gt;seize and exploit resources&lt;/strong&gt; of their neighbour or enemy, for economical reasons. What's more capitalistic than this? Yet if a "capitalist" leader commit any act of aggression, especially against poorer or communist countries, is never seen as acting on the basis of his ideology but for his own interest. We may blame the person, not capitalism. We have so engrained in our brain that capitalism &lt;strong&gt;must be good&lt;/strong&gt; that we don't think that some crimes against humanity may have been caused by it. No, it must have been that dictator that was bloodthirsty, not the economy. Money is inanimate after all, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don't grant &lt;strong&gt;so much leeway&lt;/strong&gt; to communist or nazi-fascist leaders. Every one of their mistake is a proof that their ideology is evil, inhuman and we should get rid of it for the sake of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back to Castro: when the russian installed the missiles on Cuba territory and JFK menaced war, we didn't think that Cuba, a &lt;strong&gt;sovereign state&lt;/strong&gt;, had the right to ask for military help to a friendly, sovereign too, state as URSS, to protect themselves against a powerful neighbour. No, of course the communist were the danger, so JFK was right in stepping in and prevent the installation of the missiles. If third world war had started because of the episode, we surely would have blamed Castro and Khrushchev, not Kennedy. Despite that the whole installation of missiles were done in response to the failed, american, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bay_of_Pigs_Invasion"&gt;Bay Of Pigs Invasion&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fidel Castro may be remembered as a tyrant by some and as a revolutionary by others. But step back and think if you are judging him or his ideology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/fidel_castro.jpg" alt="Fidel Castro"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo courtesy: &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/tedits/5888955648"&gt;Fidel Castro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="cuba"></category><category term="fidel castro"></category><category term="ideology"></category><category term="communism"></category><category term="capitalism"></category></entry><entry><title>Programming Isn't Easy</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/programming-isnt-easy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-04T14:44:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-07-04T14:44:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Gianluca Fiore</name></author><id>tag:www.gianlucafiore.it,2016-07-04:/blog/programming-isnt-easy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Programming.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Pair Programming"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reading, as usual, &lt;a href="http://www.hanselman.com"&gt;Scott Hanselman's blog&lt;/a&gt; and couldn't agree more on his complaining on the recent WWDC keynote asserting that programming is easy. From his &lt;a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/StopSayingLearningToCodeIsEasy.aspx"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we tell folks - kids or otherwise - that programming is easy, what will they think when it gets difficult? And it will …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Programming.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Pair Programming"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reading, as usual, &lt;a href="http://www.hanselman.com"&gt;Scott Hanselman's blog&lt;/a&gt; and couldn't agree more on his complaining on the recent WWDC keynote asserting that programming is easy. From his &lt;a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/StopSayingLearningToCodeIsEasy.aspx"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we tell folks - kids or otherwise - that programming is easy, what will they think when it gets difficult? And it will get difficult. That's where people find themselves saying "well, I guess I'm not wired for coding. It's just not for me."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly. Apple may be in dire need of finding the next Steve Jobs or any other genius programmer and in doing so is pushing the concept that anybody &lt;strong&gt;can&lt;/strong&gt; code. While this is technically true, not everybody has the skills needed to code, nor to be a &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt; coder. Especially. I'd argue that most people haven't. Scott makes a list of problems new coders should be prepared to face:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming is hard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's complicated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's exhausting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's exasperating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some things will totally make sense to you and some won't. I'm looking at you, RegEx.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The documentation usually sucks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes computers are stupid and crash. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a very optimistic list. I'd rephrase it like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming is hard because it needs you to &lt;strong&gt;think creatively&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;outside of the box&lt;/strong&gt;, most of the time. It asks you a level of openness to new ideas and concepts, even after years of practice, that many people aren't prepared for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is complicated because &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt; is interconnected. You can't be a system programmer and have no notion of what HTML is. Or a web developer who doesn't know how to access a database. You can and &lt;strong&gt;should&lt;/strong&gt; specialize but not to the point of knowing zero about what's beyond your knowledge area. You could be such a programmer but you won't be a &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt; programmer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is thus exhausting because it is not possible to exhaust the things you need to know, or possibly want to know. It is a science, and a rapidly-evolving one at that, so you can't possibly &lt;strong&gt;stop learning&lt;/strong&gt; and consider yourself done. While this is valid for many careers, I'm not talking about just updating your acquired knowledges or perfectioning some areas of your skill sets; it's a whole, long term, knowledge path that ideally lasts a lifetime. A 10 years Python expert may be a total newbie at databases and a senior Unix administrator may not know a thing about pointers in C. So it is &lt;strong&gt;necessary&lt;/strong&gt; to always learn, which can easily become exhausting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming is very exasperating. &lt;a href="http://unhelpfulerrormessages.tumblr.com"&gt;Unhelpful error messages&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@daffl/javascript-the-weird-parts-8ff3da55798e#.d24aom1g0"&gt;language oddities&lt;/a&gt; and plain lack of documentation can make you waste &lt;strong&gt;days&lt;/strong&gt; trying to make your code work. You need to be an intermediate &lt;strong&gt;stoic&lt;/strong&gt; to bear with this for years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most things &lt;strong&gt;won't make sense&lt;/strong&gt; the first time; nor the second; and, probably, not even the third. It's like learning a foreign language that has less than 10% similarity with the ones you know already. With the added difficulty that our brains are used to associate words and meanings since we are born, not to understand what is a Monad, a Map+Filter+Reduce or what is NP-hardness. It requires much more &lt;strong&gt;effort&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes, &lt;strong&gt;computers crash&lt;/strong&gt;. Worst, they may crash the first time but not the second, nor the third but the fourth and fifth yes. Don't worry, it doesn't make sense even to programming gurus. Nor it will make more sense after you learn more. It is just the way computers are. Those assholes...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd say that basic skills you need to survive all these hurdles and make it as a programmer are (in no particular order):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hundreds of hours of your life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Openness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stubbornness &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concentration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willingness to make lots of mistakes and be ok with feeling dumb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humbleness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Somebody that will bring you food when you can't leave your computer because you are trying to debug some error that happened randomly for the past week ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds &lt;strong&gt;depressing&lt;/strong&gt;? Yes. &lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt;? Oh yes. Am I too &lt;strong&gt;pessimistic&lt;/strong&gt;? Perhaps. But I don't want new coders to &lt;strong&gt;rush&lt;/strong&gt; into it thinking it was easy and creating a generation of mediocre programmers like we did with the advent of Windows with users. Not everybody has a talent for it as not everybody plays football as well as Messi. This is obvious. I don't subscribe to the notion that "everybody can make it", in any area of life. You may be an &lt;strong&gt;average programmer&lt;/strong&gt; even if you have no talent for it whatsoever after many hours of study, sure. But, is it worth it? Is it what our society &lt;strong&gt;needs&lt;/strong&gt;? Tons of &lt;strong&gt;mediocre programmers&lt;/strong&gt;? Another 20-30000 apps on the Play Store that are bugged, stupid or try to mimick the features of a better one, failing at that? Do we need &lt;strong&gt;more software&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;better software&lt;/strong&gt;? What if we stopped being so &lt;em&gt;people-consuming&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, &lt;strong&gt;I digress&lt;/strong&gt;. I'm not going to ramble against capitalism. Not now. Point is, if even after my pessimistic list you still are interested in becoming a programmer, then you may be &lt;strong&gt;passionate&lt;/strong&gt; about it. Which is wonderful. The good news is that therefore you'll make it :) Passion trumps every difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm thus going to give you some constructive advice. Much more &lt;strong&gt;optimistic&lt;/strong&gt;, I promise. Let's start:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can find &lt;strong&gt;lots of help&lt;/strong&gt; at your fingertip. Google (or, better, &lt;a href="http://duckduckgo.com"&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com"&gt;Stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt; are at your disposal. Your Linux distro of choice's forums are invaluable sources of information. There are plenty of people that find amusing to &lt;strong&gt;shoot you down&lt;/strong&gt;, sure, as there are plenty that takes bunches of their daily time to help newbies and such. Ignore the former, be thankful for the latter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tech world &lt;strong&gt;will make sense&lt;/strong&gt; to you. You'll understand how all the small pieces that make the Internet work together, why more powerful hardware doesn't automatically translate in better performances and in general acquire a great deal of knowledges about so many aspects of modern life. Knowledge is power, &lt;strong&gt;be powerful&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You'll &lt;strong&gt;create&lt;/strong&gt; tools that people will appreciate and use. This alone should be enough motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You'll keep your &lt;a href="http://www.health.harvard.edu/mind-and-mood/12-ways-to-keep-your-brain-young"&gt;brain young&lt;/a&gt; (see first item in the list). Who wants to grow old and stupid? Nobody. So &lt;strong&gt;keep learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the more practical-minded out there, the &lt;strong&gt;pay isn't bad&lt;/strong&gt; at all:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div style="width:628px; border: 1px solid #cecece; font-family: 'Open Sans'; padding:10px 0px 10px 10px;"&gt;&lt;div style="font-size:20px; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a style="text-decoration: none; color:#0066cc;" target="_blank" href="http://www.payscale.com/research/US/Job=Software_Developer/Salary"&gt;Software Developer&lt;/a&gt; (United States)&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://www.payscale.com/syndication/total_pay_chart.aspx?js=&amp;country=United+States&amp;city=&amp;state=&amp;job=Software+Developer&amp;company=&amp;width=628px&amp;chartTNG=1&amp;showfooter=1&amp;reportid=cd7f878f&amp;skills=&amp;explvl="&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;div style="float: right; padding-right: 12px;"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.payscale.com/images/small_logo_transparent.png" alt="PayScale" width="75" height="25" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-size: 13px; padding-top: 9px; font-style: italic; color: #333;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-size: 14px;"&gt;Compare your salary. &lt;a href="http://www.payscale.com/wizards/choose.aspx?TK=Embed_Lg" target="_blank" style="color: #0066cc; text-decoration: none;"&gt;Get a FREE salary report &amp;raquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try different technologies. Maybe the language you picked to start isn't really &lt;strong&gt;suited&lt;/strong&gt; to you or perhaps you are a Windows programmer more than an Unix one so you need to change your working environment to feel comfortable. Fine. Don't give up just because the first try may have been a &lt;strong&gt;wrong choice&lt;/strong&gt;. There are plenty of languages and areas out there, you'll surely find one that works for you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You'll be so frustrated, feel so dumb, so tired and so close to give up so many times that when finally you'll manage to make it work, it is the &lt;strong&gt;best feeling in the world&lt;/strong&gt;. Ok, maybe sex is better; you got what I mean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &lt;strong&gt;try it&lt;/strong&gt;. You may fail or find your passion, and a career with it. Who knows. It is truly worth it. Especially, don't let anybody tell you that you "can't" or that programming isn't "suited" to people of your race/sex/education/upbringing/mentality/whatever. No matter what others may say, &lt;strong&gt;go for it!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo Courtesy: &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/damienpollet/5048830734/"&gt;Pair Programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="programming"></category></entry><entry><title>What Nobody Tells You About Shaving With A Straight Razor</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/what-nobody-tells-you-about-shaving-with-a-straight-razor.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-29T18:04:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-06-29T18:04:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Gianluca Fiore</name></author><id>tag:www.gianlucafiore.it,2016-06-29:/blog/what-nobody-tells-you-about-shaving-with-a-straight-razor.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Most people shave with something like this &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Shaving-gillette.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Gillette Razor"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of blades may vary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps, if more inclined to use of modern technologies, with this &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Shaving-electrical.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Electrical Razor"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe, it's becoming rarer and rarer these days, you are old-fashioned or have found it in your grandfather's closet so you shave with this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Shaving-safe.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Safety Razor"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Most people shave with something like this &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Shaving-gillette.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Gillette Razor"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of blades may vary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps, if more inclined to use of modern technologies, with this &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Shaving-electrical.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Electrical Razor"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe, it's becoming rarer and rarer these days, you are old-fashioned or have found it in your grandfather's closet so you shave with this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Shaving-safe.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Safety Razor"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A double edge safety razor. Safety is an euphemism, such a razor is no way "safer" than any of the more modern ones, it was only safer than what was available before it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Shaving-straight.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Straight Razor"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is what I shave with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you may be wondering: why using such a razor instead of the previous two kinds? Aren't those fine? Yes they are but are also far from perfect. &lt;strong&gt;Electric razors&lt;/strong&gt; were very irritating for my skin, even using the ones that you shave with while showering or by moisturising the skin with a specific gel made my skin full of rashes and irritation. Not something I'd like to look in the mirror every day. &lt;strong&gt;Plain&lt;/strong&gt;, disposable, razors were better but the quality of shaving was lackluster at most: great on the cheeks and lower neck, awful on the chin and higher neck. I felt like I was only partially shaving my face every time. Also, irritations were a lesser issue but were still present. They lasted only a few days too, after 1 week shaving quality dropped considerably . &lt;strong&gt;Double-edge razors&lt;/strong&gt; didn't seem to offer great improvements over the modern Gillette-like disposable ones. Probably better shaving but you still had to substitute the blades every few days. More money, more waste of materials and more packaging to get rid of. I was unsatisfied with all shaving methods. I wanted something that could give me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better shaving quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No or minimal skin irritation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheaper (in the long run)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More environment-friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Badass factor ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Straight razors&lt;/strong&gt; seemed to fit the bill. I bought the one in the photo above on Ebay. Pretty cheap, 44€, shipping included. Shaving soap I had already, as an old brush bought years ago by my father and left unused until now. I was ready to go then. This is what I learned in the first 2 months of using exclusively a straight razor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;"Shave-ready" does NEVER mean shave-ready&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The straight razor I bought was used. It was "&lt;em&gt;mostly shave-ready&lt;/em&gt;" according to the vendor. I trusted his assumptions and proceeded to shave with it without trying to hone it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a &lt;strong&gt;bloodbath&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only until I &lt;strong&gt;honed&lt;/strong&gt; it with a couple of stones (more on this later) I realized that "shave-ready" means different things to different people and you can't really trust anybody outside of your own face's skin. That is the only real test. To sum it up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if it shaves well and comfortably, it's &lt;strong&gt;shave-ready&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if it shaves well but uncomfortably, it's &lt;strong&gt;NOT shave-ready&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if it shaves "ok", comfortably or not, it's &lt;strong&gt;NOT shave-ready&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if it doesn't shave at all, it's &lt;strong&gt;NOT shave-ready&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if there's blood all over the place, regardless of how it shaves, it's &lt;strong&gt;DEFINITELY NOT shave-ready&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only your face can tell you whether it's shave-ready or not. No other real test is enough to assess the sharpness of a blade. You shave with it, if it's comfortable and actually removes hair pretty well, it's shave-ready. Of course all this assuming that your &lt;strong&gt;technique&lt;/strong&gt; is at least &lt;strong&gt;ok&lt;/strong&gt;; in most cases it's not so check how you swing the razor, at which angle and how much pressure you are putting on your skin with it first. With an ok technique, the above list stands valid. Just &lt;strong&gt;don't discard&lt;/strong&gt; an otherwise fine razor because your technique isn't good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Which razor to buy?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It &lt;strong&gt;doesn't really matter&lt;/strong&gt;. Really. Straight razors aficionados will talk about &lt;strong&gt;Thiers-Issard&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Solingen&lt;/strong&gt; steel, &lt;strong&gt;Damascus&lt;/strong&gt; steel blades and whether &lt;strong&gt;carbon steel&lt;/strong&gt; is better than &lt;strong&gt;stainless steel&lt;/strong&gt; to no end. Forget about this for the moment. Any decent, as in free of holes, not covered in rust, razor will do as your first. Any will shave well once they are shave-ready. Buy the first you find that is within your budget, don't rush to buy the "&lt;strong&gt;best&lt;/strong&gt;" one as you may end up assuming that it should shave better than the others only because it is more famous. You could be very much deluded by it if your technique isn't on par with the quality of the blade. &lt;strong&gt;Bad technique&lt;/strong&gt; = &lt;strong&gt;bad shaving&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;good technique&lt;/strong&gt; = &lt;strong&gt;good shaving&lt;/strong&gt;. The blade isn't that important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did I say that technique is important? :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Honing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you have your brand new straight razor. Let's assume it is not really 
shave-ready, as probably it won't. How do you make it sharp and smooth 
on your skin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &lt;strong&gt;honing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And how do you hone a razor?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a &lt;strong&gt;honing stone&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, if you are not patient, &lt;strong&gt;forget&lt;/strong&gt; about honing altogether.  Buy a REALLY shave-ready razor and 2-3 times a year send it to a &lt;strong&gt;professional honer&lt;/strong&gt; to restore the sharpness. There are experts on Ebay that can make it sharp for you before shipping or you may find local ones, better, that will do it for you the first time for a few bucks. A few more money spent but a lot more time for you saved. Honing isn't something you can learn in 1 week or 1 month, and perhaps not even in 1 year; I for sure didn't master it in just 2 months. It is very complicated, it requires some level of passion to be good at it. You have been warned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing: make a shave which is rusted or has holes or any other kind of physical serious damage, shave-ready isn't honing but &lt;strong&gt;restoring&lt;/strong&gt;, and it's much more complicated. &lt;strong&gt;Don't bother&lt;/strong&gt; with that, leave those razors to experts or professionals. You'll waste a lot of time and money trying to restore such a razor without any experience.  The chances that you may fail, get frustrated and give up altogether on straight razors would be very high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let's buy also a stone. Not every stone will do, obviously. Don't start picking stones on the street hoping they will make your razor shine. It's highly probable that you'll end up &lt;strong&gt;destroying&lt;/strong&gt; it forever instead. Don't do that. Choose a stone that is made for honing. Honing stones are categorized in how many &lt;strong&gt;grits&lt;/strong&gt; they are. Grits being the level of granularity, or coarseness, they are. The lower, the more coarse a stone is. For honing a razor that has the duty of passing millimeters from your skin, you want stones that can produce a very fine edge, nothing coarse that will make your face look like butchered after a few passes. So any stone below &lt;strong&gt;1000&lt;/strong&gt; is too coarse for a razor.  Unfortunately those are the cheapest ones and the easiest to found. Life sucks sometimes, sorry. What you should aim for are stones that are between &lt;strong&gt;1200-5000&lt;/strong&gt; grits, with the best combo being 1 of 1200-1500 and another, a "&lt;strong&gt;finishing stone&lt;/strong&gt;", of 3500 or above grits. You could do with a single stone, very fine, but it depends on the original state of the razor; if it's not optimal, you may waste time trying to make a sharp edge with a stone too fine for the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, honing is &lt;strong&gt;complicated&lt;/strong&gt;. I told you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many types of stones but all can be divided in 2 main categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Natural stones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artificial stones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without going into great detail about the characteristics of each as it would make this post book-long, let's overgeneralize by saying that &lt;strong&gt;artificial stones&lt;/strong&gt; are a tad easier to use while &lt;strong&gt;natural stones&lt;/strong&gt; make a more gentle edge, resulting in a smoother shaving experience. It's a very broad generalization though.  For names, very good artificial stones are &lt;strong&gt;Nortons&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Shaptons&lt;/strong&gt; and a few Japanese brands, while natural ones are the &lt;strong&gt;Belgian Blue&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Coticule&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Thuringians&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Eschers&lt;/strong&gt; (not &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/M._C._Escher"&gt;that Escher&lt;/a&gt; ). You may mix, thus having 1 artificial and 1 natural stone to be used together. That's ok.  Actually it is even recommended as you'll get the best of both worlds. Usually the natural one will be used as the finishing stone but that's not a law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual process of honing includes lots of different techniques, a great deal of experience and tons of patience. I am not knowledgeable enough to explain it all here; I'm still practicing myself and learning each time a bit more. For a practical &lt;strong&gt;how-to&lt;/strong&gt; on honing, I'll send you, again, to the excellent page on the &lt;a href="http://straightrazorplace.com/srpwiki/index.php/Beginner's_Guide_to_Honing"&gt;Straigh Razor Place Wiki&lt;/a&gt; about honing. Just a few advices: don't put &lt;strong&gt;too much pressure&lt;/strong&gt; when swinging, do it &lt;strong&gt;slow&lt;/strong&gt;, use a &lt;strong&gt;tape&lt;/strong&gt; to protect the spine of the razor, be sure your stone is &lt;strong&gt;lapped&lt;/strong&gt; (another complicated process that is meant to make the honing stone perfectly flat) and take your &lt;strong&gt;time&lt;/strong&gt; in honing. No master honer was ever in a rush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Preparation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What, you don't &lt;strong&gt;prepare&lt;/strong&gt; your skin before shaving? No, no, no, that's not how you shave with a straight razor. Remember, this is like using a knife on your face, only sharper. It's not like with a multiblade razor that does some skin stretching for you (ever wondered what's that &lt;strong&gt;gummy part&lt;/strong&gt; before the blades for? Yeah, this) or an electric one that basically shaves on its own with you just having to pass it over your face. No. &lt;strong&gt;You are on your own here&lt;/strong&gt; and the blade is incredibly sharp (or if it's not, it should before you try shaving with it). Straight razors actually remove the first &lt;strong&gt;layer&lt;/strong&gt; of your skin along with hairs, they are more accurate, surgical accurateness, than the other razors. You got to have your skin ready for the blade. And a firm hand, but this I bet you guessed already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, use a good &lt;strong&gt;shaving cream&lt;/strong&gt;. The cheap kind is &lt;strong&gt;ok-ish&lt;/strong&gt;, it'll do at first, but you'll soon realize that those people that plays with chemicals in the backyards like they are Walter White to make their own shaving soap/cream aren't &lt;strong&gt;crazy&lt;/strong&gt;: a great soap makes moving the blade on your skin &lt;strong&gt;smoother&lt;/strong&gt;, nearly effortless. It reduces irritations when the skin isn't accustomed to the blade yet and it make possible perfect &lt;strong&gt;adherence&lt;/strong&gt; between the tip of the blade and the skin underneath, which is the situation you want to be at all times to cut with the least pressure and maximum results.&lt;br&gt;
You can use any shaving cream, it's not as important as the technique or the sharpness of the razor. You'll have great results anyway. But if you are willing to &lt;strong&gt;invest&lt;/strong&gt; in a good cream you'll have even better results. It's worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do you prepare the skin? &lt;strong&gt;Wash&lt;/strong&gt; it, thoroughly. This should be the norm with any form of shaving actually but most people forget it or are too much in a rush in the morning to dedicate the time to wash themselves as they should. Use cold or hot water, as you see fit. There's not a fixed rule here, some prefer cold and others hot. &lt;strong&gt;Experiment&lt;/strong&gt;. I prefer cold as it is less aggressive on the skin. Wash your face and apply a &lt;strong&gt;moderate&lt;/strong&gt; (no need to have 3 centimetres of cream on your face...) amount of shaving cream. Then shave. I assume that you already know the stretching part. But perhaps you never paid much attention, especially if you shave with an electric razor. You should stretch your skin in the &lt;strong&gt;opposite direction&lt;/strong&gt; you are moving the blade across your face. If going upwards, stretch the skin downwards and viceversa. Stretching will make easier for the razor to &lt;strong&gt;glide&lt;/strong&gt; on your face by making it adhere much closer to the skin and presenting a plain surface over which it can pass. Most of the "&lt;em&gt;bumps&lt;/em&gt;" you may experience while shaving with a straight razor are due to the skin not being stretched enough. &lt;strong&gt;The more the better&lt;/strong&gt; here. You have two hands and only one can wear the razor, make use of the second. Most of the time the small &lt;strong&gt;cuts&lt;/strong&gt; you may get are due to the skin not being perfectly stretched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Technique&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technique is &lt;strong&gt;king&lt;/strong&gt;. You can't assume you just swing the razor up and down and voilà your face look like a baby's ass. Not at all. Technique is huge, huge, &lt;strong&gt;HUGE&lt;/strong&gt;. Can't stress this enough. It's infinitely much better to shave with a cheap blade but with perfect technique than having the most expensive razor ever made and being a total newbie. If you don't learn at least at average levels the technique, &lt;strong&gt;you WILL cut yourself&lt;/strong&gt;. Period. I assure you. There's no room here for "oh but I am better than most men, my hand is firm...". NO! You are not, trust me! Thinking along this way will only results in a face &lt;strong&gt;crisscrossed&lt;/strong&gt; in blood. Every. Single. Time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how do you shave with a straight razor? There are 3 methods:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WTG&lt;/strong&gt;: "with the grain". You shave following the direction of the growth of the hairs. It's the &lt;strong&gt;simpler&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;safer&lt;/strong&gt; method but also the one that cuts less hairs. You usually make a first pass WTG and then do a second or even a third with the other methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XTG&lt;/strong&gt;: "across the grain". If your hairs grow horizontally, this means shaving vertically. And vice-versa. This is usually &lt;strong&gt;pretty effective&lt;/strong&gt; and enough to have a &lt;strong&gt;pretty good shaving&lt;/strong&gt;. Some don't do it though, preferring the next method along with WTG, others only do this pass and nothing else. Again, experiment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ATG&lt;/strong&gt;: "against the grain". This is where you bleed if you aren't super-careful. As you have already guessed, this method means going in the opposite direction of the growth of your beard. For most men this means going upward but there are some (like me) who have a hairs growing horizontally or obliquely so you must shave in &lt;strong&gt;different directions&lt;/strong&gt; according to which part of your face you are currently shaving. It's &lt;strong&gt;harder&lt;/strong&gt; than it seems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 3 different methods can be combined (usually it's a WTG pass followed by a ATG pass). Experiment yourself, there's no fixed rule you have to follow here. Too much depend from the skin and the directions your own hairs grow. What you have to follow is the &lt;strong&gt;cutting angle&lt;/strong&gt;: 30° for WTG passes, 15° for XTG and 5° (or even completely flat) for ATG. An image may be easier to understand:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Shaving-cutting_angles.jpg" alt="Cutting Angles"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find the blade isn't moving or bumps here and there, it's nearly always because of a wrong angle. Check it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Stropping&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you have now shaved with your new straight razor, with whatever technique you chose, washed your face from cream remnants and feel pretty &lt;strong&gt;smug&lt;/strong&gt; that you have learned a nearly forgotten art from your granddaddy time. You think you are done now, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to &lt;strong&gt;strop&lt;/strong&gt; the razor. After washing it and removing any drop of water left on the blade (water leads to rust, there should never be any water on the razor after use). But what's stropping and what's it for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stropping is the process of "&lt;strong&gt;straightening&lt;/strong&gt;" the blade. Contrarily to honing, which is the process of creating an edge to a blade that hasn't one or restoring a damaged one, stropping is simply a &lt;strong&gt;maintenance&lt;/strong&gt; process for a blade. It &lt;strong&gt;re-aligns the blade edge&lt;/strong&gt; after a shave. Every time you shave with a straight razor, the blade gets slightly bent or chipped. You can't see it and it may seem weird that a bunch of hairs can chip a metal blade but they do, all the time. Stropping doesn't remove material as honing does, it just prevent the edge to bend too much and removes micro-chippings that may have been created by shaving. If you didn't strop, over time, usually a few weeks, the blade would lose its edge, be less sharp and consequently, shave worse. You won't harm yourself if you don't strop, but you'll need to &lt;strong&gt;hone it again&lt;/strong&gt; to have a comfortable and efficient shaving experience again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To strop then you need a &lt;strong&gt;razor strop&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a strip, usually a few centimeters wide and half an arm long, made of leather (sorry vegans!) that may or may not have a second side of linen, webbed fabric or cotton. The leather side is what is used to stropping, the other side is like a finishing side, after stropping, or needed before it, when you have a &lt;strong&gt;dull&lt;/strong&gt; blade that is not very sharp but not as bad as needing honing again. A borderline blade, so to say.  Some people find this second side, with a different fabric material, useful, others don't. For beginners, just care about buying a good strop with &lt;strong&gt;good quality leather&lt;/strong&gt; and forget about any second side. You just need the first, really. Don't make it too complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stropping is performed by passing your razor over the strop, leather side, a few times (I use 20 for each side of the razor) to keep its sharpness.  Nearly all strops have a way to be hanged somewhere. Exception being &lt;strong&gt;paddle strops&lt;/strong&gt; which are to be put on a &lt;strong&gt;firm surface&lt;/strong&gt; like a table.  &lt;strong&gt;Avoid&lt;/strong&gt; them, unless you are absolutely sure you won't have available a stable, non-moving point in your house. You could try using a door handle or similar, but it will make stropping more difficult as it won't be as stable.  Hold, strongly, the other side of the strop with your free hand and start passing your razor, with the &lt;strong&gt;spine first!&lt;/strong&gt;, over the strops' surface, back and forth, until it restores its sharpness. The exact movements are a bit complicated to explain but &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Shaving-stropping.gif" alt="Stropping technique"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;will make it clear for everybody: pass the razor over the strop with the spine first and never let the edge pass alone, with or without pressure from your hand. Don't press too much, let the blade glide over the leather. If it doesn't pass smoothly, you aren't doing it correctly (or the strop is damaged or of bad quality). Be easy on the blade, you aren't trying to &lt;strong&gt;remove&lt;/strong&gt; any metal, just prevent it becoming dull.  There's no need to apply even a quarter of the pressure you would when honing it, be gentle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with shaving, there are different &lt;strong&gt;techniques&lt;/strong&gt; you may implement when stropping. Diagonal, straight, zig-zag, etc. I won't explain them, I don't believe they are that &lt;strong&gt;important&lt;/strong&gt;. Do it straight for now, experience will tell you when and if to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes some practice to know for certain how long, how many passes, you need to perform good maintenance on your blade. It depends also on how long is your beard, how hard are your hairs and the kind of shaving cream you are using. Too many factors. I stabilized on &lt;strong&gt;20 passes per side&lt;/strong&gt; and it seems ok, most of the days. Again, experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Finishing touches&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After shaving, washing and stropping, you're nearly done. Remove any residual water there may be on your razor with a cloth, put it back wherever you chose to as long as it's not near any form of water or under direct sun; keep your strop dry too and remember to wet your natural honing stones once in a while to not let them completely dry (they may &lt;strong&gt;crack&lt;/strong&gt; otherwise).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You're finally done. Most definitely your first shave with a straight razor won't be as &lt;strong&gt;satisfying&lt;/strong&gt; nor &lt;strong&gt;accurate&lt;/strong&gt; as you'd expect. Check your technique. With more experience, it will improve and with it the shaving quality. Don't be discouraged if after some days or weeks you feel that you aren't shaving as good as you were with your previous shaving method. It's normal. This is closer to an &lt;strong&gt;art&lt;/strong&gt;, a long and nearly lost art, than the other methods. Nobody could be a great painter or musician in a week. Be gentle and patient and better results will come. To keep yourself motivated, keep in mind that there's no other shaving method that can approach the smoothness and accurateness that a straight razor will give you after you mastered the art. No one.  Enjoy the feeling of having a smooth as a baby face and having been nice to the environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S.: infinite thanks to the &lt;a href="http://www.straightrazorplace.com"&gt;Straight Razor Place&lt;/a&gt; community for the astounding amount of passion and info poured into the art of shaving. Invaluable help for any beginners&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo Courtesy: 
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/qiaomeng/5557993124/"&gt;Gillette&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/teoruiz/83474508/"&gt;Electrical 
Razor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/rewillard/593222260/"&gt;Safety 
Razor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/rpscott123/4133793660/"&gt;Straight Razor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="shaving"></category><category term="razor"></category><category term="art"></category><category term="life"></category></entry><entry><title>Classic Cocktails Cheat Sheet</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/classic-cocktails-cheat-sheet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-26T11:44:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-04-26T11:44:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Gianluca Fiore</name></author><id>tag:www.gianlucafiore.it,2016-04-26:/blog/classic-cocktails-cheat-sheet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I've become the maintainer, and main contributor, of &lt;a href="https://duck.co/ia/view/classic_cocktails_cheat_sheet"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; DuckDuckGo's Instant answer. It has been deployed on &lt;a href="https://beta.duckduckgo.com"&gt;beta.duckduckgo.com&lt;/a&gt; only so far, as it is clearly just a beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/cocktail_ddg.jpg" width="1024" height="765" 
alt="Classic Cocktails IA screenshot"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My passion for cocktails and carefully mixed drinks is no mistery and thus it was only …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I've become the maintainer, and main contributor, of &lt;a href="https://duck.co/ia/view/classic_cocktails_cheat_sheet"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; DuckDuckGo's Instant answer. It has been deployed on &lt;a href="https://beta.duckduckgo.com"&gt;beta.duckduckgo.com&lt;/a&gt; only so far, as it is clearly just a beta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/cocktail_ddg.jpg" width="1024" height="765" 
alt="Classic Cocktails IA screenshot"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My passion for cocktails and carefully mixed drinks is no mistery and thus it was only natural to write such an IA for DuckDuckGo, my main search engine since a few years. It is incomplete, I only wanted to add &lt;em&gt;classic&lt;/em&gt; cocktails, not all, and there are a few doubts on the format of the recipes among the community (see the &lt;a href="https://github.com/duckduckgo/zeroclickinfo-goodies/pull/2796"&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt;). Namely, the sempiternal question about ounces, millilitres and parts. I side with the parts team but I'm writing this post also to call for anyone interested to express his/her opinions and submit new or better recipes. Any improvement or suggestion is appreciated, let's get this IA out of beta!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="duckduckgo"></category><category term="cocktail"></category><category term="drink"></category><category term="cheat sheet"></category><category term="search engine"></category></entry><entry><title>Back To Naples</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/back-to-naples.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-15T11:04:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-02-15T11:04:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Gianluca Fiore</name></author><id>tag:www.gianlucafiore.it,2016-02-15:/blog/back-to-naples.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last month I went back to my &lt;strong&gt;hometown&lt;/strong&gt;, Naples, for New Year's Eve. Meeting with family and showing the city to girlfriend. A very enjoyable week, I have to say, fun, drinks, good food, visiting as a tourist your old home and rejoining with 2 lovely cats at home :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Napoli-lungomare.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Naples"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last month I went back to my &lt;strong&gt;hometown&lt;/strong&gt;, Naples, for New Year's Eve. Meeting with family and showing the city to girlfriend. A very enjoyable week, I have to say, fun, drinks, good food, visiting as a tourist your old home and rejoining with 2 lovely cats at home :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Napoli-lungomare.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Naples"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip reinforced my &lt;strong&gt;love-hate&lt;/strong&gt; relationship with Naples. The food is &lt;strong&gt;outstanding&lt;/strong&gt;, it is really, really hard to find another city with same quality food as Naples, no doubts. People are generally warm and welcoming, open for a chat at any moment and with a hint of humanity that you don't get that often in north Italy (your mileage may vary, of course). The city is artistically rich, beautiful in a decadent way, there are still plenty of unknown to tourists places to discover, the view from Posillipo or the Vesuvio is &lt;strong&gt;breathtaking&lt;/strong&gt; and art is everywhere around you, as usual in Italy. &lt;strong&gt;Cheap&lt;/strong&gt; prices to eat out, a new, modern metro system and the best pizza in the world complete the offer of the city to visitors. It is also nearly impossible to find another city in the world which has the same quantity and quality of day trip to make: from Pompeii (and Ercolano), to Vesuvio, to Capri, Sorrento, the Amalfi coast with Positano and Caserta with its "&lt;em&gt;italian Versailles&lt;/em&gt;".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the &lt;strong&gt;love&lt;/strong&gt; part. I'd add, which is personal, memories and a lively musical background that no other city in Italy can offer. Yes, no other, only Naples has songs in neapolitan, its dialect, that are regularly sang by the best tenors/sopranos all around the world for more than a century. Everybody knows '&lt;strong&gt;O Sole Mio&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;'O Surdato Innamurato&lt;/strong&gt;. Italian music, well renowed for its melodies and good voices, was sparkled in late 19th century by Neapolitan music after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and Maradona. Which is another name for God, didn't you know? ;) (it has even a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iglesia_Maradoniana"&gt;Church&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Napoli-Maradona_altar.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="God amongst various fake idols"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then there's the &lt;strong&gt;hate&lt;/strong&gt; part, which inevitably presents itself after a few days and the "honeymoon" effect of the first moments has passed. In just a week I faced, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taximen who claimed they were making you a favour to carry you back home, in the suburbs. Get my money and shut up, please&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ice creams thrown away on the streets on a regular basis (what's wrong with a nice &lt;em&gt;gelato&lt;/em&gt; people?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;people walking in all directions, with no apparent final destination. You have to go left, and then right, and then walk in the center, randomly, just because some people have no idea where they're going to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;speaking of which, nobody has a clue how to find some monuments because there are &lt;strong&gt;no signs&lt;/strong&gt; indicating them. And good luck finding any signs that are in english...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no &lt;strong&gt;respect&lt;/strong&gt; whatsoever for normal rules on the streets. You go where you want and stop where and when you want, this is the only rule accepted by everybody in Naples. Clearly driving becomes an hellish experience as you don't have any right to pass before any other driver, you have to &lt;strong&gt;take&lt;/strong&gt; that right from the other driver or he/she'll take it from you. It's like a Sergio Leone western with cars instead of guns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;road surfaces are uneven. &lt;strong&gt;Holes&lt;/strong&gt;, access to sewage system/electrical cables/telecommunication cables/water and different kinds of pavements make it impossible to find a road that has more than half a meter &lt;strong&gt;100%&lt;/strong&gt; straight. It is amazing how it is possible to repair roads every few months and still not having a single one that is really straight. In Naples roads are repaired to fix the previous repairing, which in turn fixed an even older one. It is a never ending story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The astute reader may be thinking now that all this applies to &lt;strong&gt;other italian cities&lt;/strong&gt; too. That's true. Any big city, at least from Rome (included) to south, has the same problems as Naples, if not in some areas even worse. But none of them has been a &lt;strong&gt;splendid&lt;/strong&gt; city just a little more than 100 years ago and rapidly decayed after it was annexed to the Kingdom of Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure now many will think that &lt;strong&gt;Rome&lt;/strong&gt; has had the same destiny of Naples. Flourished for centuries until the Kingdom of Italy became a reality. &lt;strong&gt;Wrong&lt;/strong&gt;. Rome hadn't been politically and economically relevant since Charlemagne era, at least, 1200 years earlier. The only rich peoples were priests and local aristocracy, and they fuelled a lot of art, as you can see today, but normal peasants were poor, merchants didn't cross it as it was not on the sea and had nothing peculiar to offer to foreign investors. The &lt;strong&gt;Papal State&lt;/strong&gt; was also of no military importance and never grow up more than the size of 2-3 regions of nowadays Italy. As an example, &lt;strong&gt;Florence&lt;/strong&gt;, to the north, was as much as magnet for artists as Rome but its princesses married emperors and kings all around europe and it had a play in many international alliances from Middle Age till the Renaissance, if not even after. Rome has been in a decaying state since 4-500 years at least. Which is sad as it is an &lt;strong&gt;amazingly&lt;/strong&gt; beautiful city. But I digress...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naples, instead, has been important throughout its history. From Roman times, when it hosted the main &lt;strong&gt;imperial fleet&lt;/strong&gt;, was a center of Greek-Hellenistic culture and considered the capital of the best region in Italy ("Campania Felix" anyone?), through Middle Ages with the founding of the &lt;strong&gt;first public university&lt;/strong&gt; of the world in 1224, a growing population (up to &lt;strong&gt;300.000 inhabitants&lt;/strong&gt; around 16th century), and being the biggest and richest city of the biggest realm of the time, Spain, second only after its capital, Madrid. In more recent times, the richness and importance of the city was shown by the building of the &lt;strong&gt;first modern opera&lt;/strong&gt; house among the biggest italian cities, San Carlo theatre (1737, yes, before La Scala in Milan), the very &lt;strong&gt;first railway in Italy&lt;/strong&gt;, Napoli-Portici, and second in the world (1839), the &lt;strong&gt;oldest volcanology observatory&lt;/strong&gt; in the world right on the way to Vesuvio's top (1841) and being the &lt;strong&gt;biggest&lt;/strong&gt; italian city, and third in Europe after Paris and Vienna, for nearly 300 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today Naples is instead more famous for its &lt;strong&gt;dirtiness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Napoli-street.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Napoli street"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the powerful organized crime (&lt;strong&gt;Camorra&lt;/strong&gt; or "Il Sistema" as its adherent calls it), magistrally depicted in the movie and then tv series &lt;strong&gt;Gomorra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Napoli-Gomorra.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Gomorra tv series"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;commonly sneered about by northern italians, to &lt;strong&gt;racism-levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Napoli_is_not_italy.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="The always lovely Juventus football fans..."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and lack of jobs and general lower than average &lt;strong&gt;salaries&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did it happen? It goes beyond the scope of this post to explain it, countless books have been written on the history of south Italy after the reunification of Italy. Google "la questione meridionale" if you can read italian to get illuminated. What makes me suffer is that many neapolitans don't &lt;strong&gt;know&lt;/strong&gt; even half the informations I've exposed here and half of them don't feel any &lt;strong&gt;proudness&lt;/strong&gt; nor enthusiasm in being born in such a city. They suffer from a mix of &lt;strong&gt;ignorance&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;melancholia&lt;/strong&gt; and lack of &lt;strong&gt;hope&lt;/strong&gt;. It's so common to think that "Naples has always been like this" that it's astounding that the city can still produce great artists and attract big investors (latest one, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2016/01/21Apple-Opening-Europes-First-iOS-App-Development-Center-in-Italy.html"&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;). It shows that among all the pain, problems and corruption, the population is inventive, smart and civil after all, at least a good slice of it. There's a strong identification between the population and the city, many neapolitans consider themselves "first neapolitan, then italian". It's a &lt;strong&gt;me-against-the-others&lt;/strong&gt; attitude, born out of feeling of having being robbed of a glorious past and given a mediocre present. From the capital of the most powerful kingdom in the italian peninsula to the third city of a republic whose powers and interests lay mostly in Rome (political) and Milan (economical). Naples was left with &lt;strong&gt;nothing&lt;/strong&gt; to be proud of in just a couple of decades after the italian reunification, not even the role of the most important harbour (that title goes to Genoa nowadays).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the first quality that comes to mind about Naples is having the best &lt;strong&gt;pizza&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/Napoli-pizza.jpg" width="1024" height="765" alt="Pizza neapolitan style"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very little for a city with such a long and prominent past. It is of no surprise then that neapolitans have such a strong feeling of revenge against the North italians who "stole our money", "sneer at us" and "emarginate us". That feeling was embodied in sport, when the greatest footballer of all times, &lt;strong&gt;Diego Armando Maradona&lt;/strong&gt;, led Napoli football team to win the italian league twice against the "evil" powers of the north, Juventus, Inter and Milan. It had never happened before for a team south of Rome to win the league and that event back in the '80s was and still is the most dear in the minds of every neapolitan. If Naples couldn't compete anymore as a political entity, in the industries or in commerce, at least it could in football. Years of shaming and discomfort were fuelled in the victories on the pitch and the main author of them was raised to &lt;strong&gt;God-like&lt;/strong&gt; levels by the local population. It was a &lt;em&gt;"si, se puede!"&lt;/em&gt; moment for the entire city, which though quickly returned to normality after Maradona left the club. Ephemeral, fleeting, transitory. Sure. But &lt;strong&gt;powerful&lt;/strong&gt;, very powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what pains me the most. That neapolitans could summon so much joy and enthusiasm for sport successes but can't to make the city better. We can fight &lt;strong&gt;against&lt;/strong&gt; something, to be better than somebody who we feel has mistreated us, but we can't fight for &lt;strong&gt;ourselves&lt;/strong&gt;, to improve our standard of living. This we'd need to learn to be back where we were. We lost the capacity to believe that just ourselves can make our future great, without waiting for help from the central government or saints. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"Se Dio vuole"&lt;/em&gt; is a very common phrase to be heard in Naples. It means, "if God wants". At which I always reply: &lt;em&gt;"why shouldn't he want?"&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photos courtesy: &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/manfrys/13896608865/"&gt;Napoli Lungomare&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/131948873@N07/19170987655/"&gt;Napoli Street&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/95268887@N00/263753643/"&gt;Pizza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="naples"></category><category term="napoli"></category><category term="italy"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="life"></category></entry><entry><title>terminalCV</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/terminalcv.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-05T11:44:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-10-05T11:44:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Gianluca Fiore</name></author><id>tag:www.gianlucafiore.it,2015-10-05:/blog/terminalcv.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This goes into the "software I'm going to hack on" category. As the &lt;a href="https://github.com/hauckd"&gt;author&lt;/a&gt; says, terminalCV is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A command line CV for sysadmins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The due screenshot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/terminalcv.jpg" width="662" height="823" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To see it in action click on the new link on the sidebar, &lt;strong&gt;TerminalCV&lt;/strong&gt;. Being a lover of all things CLI, I found terminalCV …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This goes into the "software I'm going to hack on" category. As the &lt;a href="https://github.com/hauckd"&gt;author&lt;/a&gt; says, terminalCV is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A command line CV for sysadmins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The due screenshot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/terminalcv.jpg" width="662" height="823" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To see it in action click on the new link on the sidebar, &lt;strong&gt;TerminalCV&lt;/strong&gt;. Being a lover of all things CLI, I found terminalCV a great idea, not just for sysadmins but for developers in general (altough you can reason that for developers there's already Github). I'm planning to add a few features to it, like non-programming skills, and themeing (which I suck at usually but it's just a CLI so it's not that complicated :) ).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="terminal"></category><category term="cli"></category><category term="cv"></category><category term="programming"></category></entry><entry><title>First Months In Poland</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/first-months-in-poland.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-15T17:33:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-09-15T17:33:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Gianluca Fiore</name></author><id>tag:www.gianlucafiore.it,2015-09-15:/blog/first-months-in-poland.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/sky-blue-flag-poland.jpg" width="1024" height="765" 
alt="Poland Flag"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may, or probably may not, know, I've moved to &lt;strong&gt;Poland&lt;/strong&gt; last April.
Don't bother asking why as I'm still looking for an answer to.
There are a few good reasons, which I'm sure the male readers will have
already come up with, but it was mostly an instinctive …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/sky-blue-flag-poland.jpg" width="1024" height="765" 
alt="Poland Flag"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may, or probably may not, know, I've moved to &lt;strong&gt;Poland&lt;/strong&gt; last April.
Don't bother asking why as I'm still looking for an answer to.
There are a few good reasons, which I'm sure the male readers will have
already come up with, but it was mostly an instinctive decision. And I'm 
not regretting it so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are quite a few &lt;strong&gt;differences&lt;/strong&gt; between living in Poland and in my 
home country, Italy. Besides the obvious different climate, there are 
some totally unexpected or not exactly what I expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;: these are just my experiences. I claim not to have a perfect 
nor complete understanding of Polish customs and society. Take 
everything following with a pinch of salt (or, better, two).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Poles drink. A lot&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true"  href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/paszczak000/2541799082/in/photolist-4SBoj7-7Zenu-74rXD1-5cSV1i-74sfwS-icqv8-geUCL-9c7DdG-74skcQ-74rDpE-72XXFb-74oJtV-89WoQb-74nNc8-7q7YKf-8i3URw-gim6Y7-9LMutP-geUD1-91Yyeu-8xCkCX-qE5oe2-pHfcaS-PRqpX-9DqD4A-74nXyn-74nUiK-9YGAQ3-74p8NB-74sMDU-67rrkh-6CYUxb-9DqCLm-74z869-cCr6om-2PMEC-ELEQeb-PRuwg-55QBNh-rtesbe-K67JM-72UeCr-4S1RmD-hNzNFb-PRspR-2wJXk-5ypsG2-abifUo-FbWBHQ-67rxPC" title="Vodka Sobieski"&gt;&lt;img src="https://c3.staticflickr.com/4/3283/2541799082_69c63fc6c6_b.jpg" width="680" height="1024" alt="Vodka Sobieski"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poland is 
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_alcohol_consumption_per_capita"&gt;13th&lt;/a&gt; 
on the list of annual alcohol consumption per capita. Not surprising at 
all. But if you actually come here you will realize the why: alcohol is 
everywhere. You need a bottle of whisky at 03:00? No problem, hit up one 
of the thousands of &lt;strong&gt;Alkohole 24h&lt;/strong&gt; shops all around Poland and you will 
find everything from whisky to beer to wine to soft drinks to make 
cocktails with your favourite spirit. Or, are you driving and forgot to 
bring along the beer? &lt;em&gt;Nie ma problemu&lt;/em&gt;, there's alcohol at most gas 
stations too! I've been told there was in discussion a law to prohibit 
selling alcohol in those places but it caused so much outrage that the 
proposal was taken back. Seeing a lone driver buying 6 cans of beer for 
a 1 hour drive on a highway isn't uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main thing is, even if most Poles don't like to admit that they drink 
much, &lt;strong&gt;they do&lt;/strong&gt;. All of them. Young and old. I can't count how many old 
ladies I found buying spirits at the nearby supermarket. Old in their 
sixties. And I mean spirits, not just wine and beer. They go straight to 
the strong stuff. Yet I didn't see more drunkards on the streets. No more 
than London or Paris. Not even on Saturday nights there are many scenes 
of girls throwing up in the middle of the streets or guys being 
obnoxious after too many drinks. Despite drinking a lot, they have quite 
an high tolerance to alcohol (to the dismay of many foreigner men 
thinking of having an easy time with the girls...). This makes for 
alcoholism being a &lt;strong&gt;lesser problem&lt;/strong&gt; than you'd expect considering the 
sheer amount of alcohol being ingested by the local population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet it is seen as a huge problem by the politicians: everywhere along 
the "no smoking allowed" signs there are also "no alcohol allowed" 
signs. Even where you wouldn't expect, like buses or public restrooms.
Drinking is just part of their &lt;strong&gt;culture&lt;/strong&gt;, it is not unusual to be stopped
on the streets by poor people asking for 2-3 złoty "for vodka". 
Especially if you look rich or foreigner. They don't bother you much, 
just saying no is enough to stop them asking. And I appreciate the 
honesty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;There are no rules regarding eating&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an italian, I'm used to have breakfast, lunch around &lt;strong&gt;12:00-14:00&lt;/strong&gt;, 
maybe aperitif around &lt;strong&gt;17:00-19:00&lt;/strong&gt; and dinner at &lt;strong&gt;19:00-21:00&lt;/strong&gt;. Some 
exceptions can be done because of work, obviously, but those are the 
general times we eat. Conscious exceptions are frowned upon or 
considered weird. And we have a very strict etiquette about food, like 
salads come after the main dish, you don't eat bread with pasta, no 
cappuccino after 12:00 (looking at you 'mericans...), spirits/liqueurs 
are to be drank at the end of the meal etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poles &lt;strong&gt;don't give a shit&lt;/strong&gt; about those rules. The only meal you can be sure 
they have is breakfast: at &lt;strong&gt;home&lt;/strong&gt;. Hardly any Poles have breakfast at a 
bar. The most they do is grabbing a coffee on the go but they have 
already eaten something before leaving home. Which is way more healthy 
btw and I hope the hordes of Starbucks, Costa Coffe, KFC and such won't 
change it ever. This is a custom that I'd like everybody to follow, 
actually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lunch? They call it &lt;em&gt;obiad&lt;/em&gt; and is anywhere between &lt;strong&gt;12:00&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;17:00&lt;/strong&gt;. Which 
means it gets mixed with "supper", usually from &lt;strong&gt;17:00 till 22:00&lt;/strong&gt;. 
Or, more commonly, anytime they have a moment to eat. Ah, don't call it 
dinner as that means also &lt;em&gt;obiad&lt;/em&gt;, but use &lt;em&gt;kolacja&lt;/em&gt;, which is awfully 
close to the italian &lt;em&gt;colazione&lt;/em&gt;, breakfast, to my utter confusion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, just eat when you want and you'll be fine in Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rules&lt;/strong&gt; at the table? Nothing of this sort. I've seen everything, from ice 
cubes being added to wine (&lt;em&gt;"it's not cold enough!"&lt;/em&gt;), to the omnipresent 
cappuccino along with pasta, to cooking pasta with a broth cube (!), to 
eating salad, then soup, then cake, then fruits and then potatoes, to 
eating salad along with pasta/pizza/soup because "we Poles like to mix 
things up". Even ordering a pint of beer &lt;strong&gt;together with&lt;/strong&gt; a glass of 
vodka and happily sipping either, alternatively. The italian in me dies 
a little bit whenever I see something along those lines. I will have to 
become Polish very soon or risk dying altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Food quality isn't great&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I'm spoiled by &lt;strong&gt;growing up&lt;/strong&gt; in Italy but I am having an hard time 
finding a supermarket that sells good quality food. Especially fruits, 
seafood and meat. I had expected before coming here to have good meat at 
least as polish cuisine is heavily meat-based but no, it's hard to find 
any cut that is not nearly tasteless, often even the most expensive ones 
are bland in flavours. And I'm used to tens of different cuts, even at 
supermarkets. Here it seems they use the same 6-7 cuts for cooking every 
meat dish, which is &lt;strong&gt;baffling&lt;/strong&gt;.  Cheeses are fine, albeit most are 
imported. Try the &lt;strong&gt;Lithuanian cheeses&lt;/strong&gt;. Vegetables are ok, fruits is not 
but for the delicious apples (but I don't like them so I'm screwed). I 
have no idea why a banana becomes dark in 2 days here when in Italy 
takes 4-5 days (and it's hotter there too). They also suffer from the 
same problem of Germany: they have tens of different kinds of bread but 
&lt;strong&gt;no clue&lt;/strong&gt; how to bake it. I'd kill for a slice of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pane_di_Altamura"&gt;Altamura 
Bread&lt;/a&gt;. Here are the 
usual dark, rye, bread-with-some-nuts-or-seeds in/on kind of breads that 
dominate the market. For really good baked bread you have to go up in 
the ladder of quality (and cost).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Butter and margarina are aplenty and good. Olive oil is expensive, as 
you could expect. They sell &lt;strong&gt;enormously-sized yeast&lt;/strong&gt;, 75-100g, which I 
wonder still what they use it for as the most they bake are Pierogi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kitchenwench/3254936910/" 
title="Strawberry and Farmer&amp;#x27;s Cheese Pierogis"&gt;&lt;img 
src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3098/3254936910_8de497156b_o.jpg" 
width="1024" height="765" alt="Strawberry and Farmer&amp;#x27;s Cheese 
Pierogis"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pizza can be surprisingly good, I know a couple of places where it is 
&lt;strong&gt;really good&lt;/strong&gt;. No, they aren't even run by italian, real polish pizzerias. 
Fish is nowhere to be seen, especially at restaurants. In supermarkets 
is always frozen and imported but for salmon and sardines. Generally, 
avoid it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Foreigners are still weird&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poles aren't used to meet foreigners. Being on the other side of the 
&lt;strong&gt;Iron Curtain&lt;/strong&gt; for nearly half a century and immediately after 2 decades of 
&lt;strong&gt;emigration&lt;/strong&gt; has made Poland one of the countries with the &lt;strong&gt;fewest&lt;/strong&gt; number of 
immigrants in EU. Something along the lines of 700.000 foreigners among 
38 millions of Poles. If you take into account that most of those are 
Ukrainian immigrants, who visually are very close to Poles, being a 
mediterranean-looking guy means I am looked at with a mix of curiosity 
(most of the time), interest (sometime), aversity (more than seems sane 
to), hate (a couple of times). I stand out very clearly among the local 
population, it's impossible for me to pass as a Polish citizen of Polish 
ancestry (only for a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polska_Roma"&gt;Polska 
Roma&lt;/a&gt; maybe).
While this can have its advantages (&lt;em&gt;"hey look, an italian guy!"&lt;/em&gt;), it's 
very &lt;strong&gt;unsettling&lt;/strong&gt; at times to be looked at by men and women of all ages 
just because they seem to never or very rarely having seen a 
dark-skinned man. It never happened to me anywhere else in the world, 
not even as a white man in Dominican Republic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, despite my different look, Poles are so little used to meet 
foreigners that 99,9% of the time I'm &lt;strong&gt;first addressed in Polish&lt;/strong&gt; and only 
after they realize I don't understand, in English. Even in touristic places 
like the Palac Kultury i Nauki, where they'd expect to see many 
foreigner tourists, I was first addressed in Polish. Sometimes I wonder 
if it's more not being used to foreigners or not being able to conceive 
why somebody who is not polish would come to live in Poland. I've been 
asked many times why I chose Poland over Italy and so far I couldn't 
come with a definite, credible answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shows also how many Poles consider their country ugly and/or 
uninteresting. Which I disagree with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Communist Blocks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/photobeppus/8300737041/" 
title="Warszawa"&gt;&lt;img 
src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8215/8300737041_544d562c5e_b.jpg" 
width="1024" height="768" alt="Warszawa"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async 
src="//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" 
charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They're &lt;strong&gt;everywhere&lt;/strong&gt;. Nearly all Polish cities were mostly or totally 
destroyed during WWII and the communist governments following it had to 
rebuild a lot of lost housing. They followed the example of Soviet 
Russia and built those enormous, grey, squared-windows blocks 
everywhere, in every city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's face it, they are &lt;strong&gt;not pretty&lt;/strong&gt;. And Poles know it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, they aren't as bad looking as some examples of western 
architecture that you can see in the peripheries of Madrid, Rome or San 
Francisco. They have a bad reputation for being "the ugliest ones" but 
it's not rightfully earned, there are &lt;strong&gt;worst buildings&lt;/strong&gt; in the so called 
"first world" countries. Only they may look uglier because they are much 
bigger (some have like 4 stairwells and 8 different entrances for the 
same building) and really everywhere. Put a single ugly building in a 
pretty city and it will look like a mistake; put tens of ugly buildings 
in a single city and the whole city will look bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, they are extremely &lt;strong&gt;functionals&lt;/strong&gt;. Communists apparently hated lifts so 
most of them which are less than 6-7 floors have none. Some have 
installed one after the coming of democracy. So no lifts for shorter 
buildings. But the stairs are &lt;strong&gt;large&lt;/strong&gt;. The steps aren't too tall or too 
narrow. I bet some russian architect made a research on this and found 
the precise size they should be. My 42 EU size feet fits perfectly. 
Amazing. Main building door is 99% of the time activated by an 
electronic system where you press the number of your apartment, the key 
button and a 4 digit code to open the door. Alternatively, there's the 
key. It's a bit like in Ukraine but over there is still mechanical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the rooms inside are &lt;strong&gt;warm&lt;/strong&gt;. Very. The external walls are thick while 
the walls separating two apartments are not, which helps to keep the 
cold away and sharing the heating warmness from apartment to adjacent 
apartment (and also hearing the discussions of your neighbours). Every 
building has a &lt;strong&gt;basement&lt;/strong&gt;, including new ones, where you can store some of your 
stuff, included in the rent. Also most if not all have a stair to access 
the roof which Poles don't use it at all as I haven't seen anybody on 
any roof in 5 months of staying (and it was during summer). A large part 
of all buildings have room to park the car/bike in front or on the back 
of them, many green areas around and occasionally a &lt;strong&gt;recreational 
area&lt;/strong&gt; with basketball court, ping pong table and entertainment area for 
children. Speaking of which, I've seen toys inside bank offices, in 
every airport and even in a few big shops. They do care about the 
children (but they don't make 
&lt;a href="http://www.indexmundi.com/facts/poland/birth-rate"&gt;many anymore&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Beds&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bed is a bed. &lt;strong&gt;This is a bed&lt;/strong&gt; (as the wise cat clearly agrees):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/koldre/544234299" title="Ikea Mandal 
Bed"&gt;&lt;img 
src="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1154/544234299_dcfc309eb5_b.jpg" 
width="819" height="1024" alt="Ikea Mandal Bed"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async 
src="//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" 
charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anything else isn't&lt;/strong&gt;. In Poland they often try to sell you a &lt;strong&gt;sofa-bed&lt;/strong&gt; for 
a bed. It is not, dear Polish friends; it's just a sofa that can be 
opened and you can sleep on. That doesn't make it a bed as much as being 
able to sleep on an airplane seat make it a proper bed. Understood?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Language&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every foreigner here has to face it on a day to day basis: &lt;strong&gt;Polish is 
hard&lt;/strong&gt;. And every foreigner complains about it. And every Poles understand 
it's impossible to master it in less than &lt;strong&gt;1 year&lt;/strong&gt;. Or &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I don't think it needs so long at all. 1 year is a good 
guess for most, intelligent, people. 2 only if you don't give studying 
Polish much time or are very bad at languages in general. The worst part 
are the many &lt;strong&gt;declension cases&lt;/strong&gt; (which was expected) and the &lt;strong&gt;pronunciation&lt;/strong&gt; 
(which was not): one dipthong like &lt;em&gt;"rz"&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;"sz"&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;"cz"&lt;/em&gt;, or difficult sounds 
like &lt;em&gt;"ł"&lt;/em&gt; are easy enough to pronounce (and they don't change according 
to the position!), but when more than 1 is present in a single word my 
brain spins. Try to pronounce words like &lt;strong&gt;"Szczebrzeszynie"&lt;/strong&gt; or 
&lt;strong&gt;"chrząszcz"&lt;/strong&gt; (but have first at hand the number of your otolaryngologist 
for when your tongue gets stuck).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So get ready to use &lt;em&gt;"nie mowie po polsku"&lt;/em&gt; (I don't speak Polish) very 
often and take aside 1 hour each day to study Polish if you are serious 
about staying in Poland. Which it is supposed to be your duty as a 
modern, globalized citizen of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I know most won't care, so &lt;strong&gt;English will be your anchor&lt;/strong&gt;. Luckily for 
them, 90% of the younger generations, &amp;lt;30yo, know basic to average 
english. Some have really amazing english levels. Yet it's not 
Netherlands or Scandinavia, as soon as you are outside of the most 
touristic areas even speaking with 20yo people will become hard if not 
totally impossible. There's a huge &lt;strong&gt;gap&lt;/strong&gt; between well educated people and 
those who have average or lower than average education: the english of 
the latter will be at most basic, if not that bad that they could as 
well speak polish. If you consider that many 40+ well educated people 
&lt;strong&gt;didn't study english at school&lt;/strong&gt; at all (because, Russians!), you can 
imagine how small is the population range that a foreigner can have a 
normal discussion in english. The situation is clearly improving, in 20 
years you could live here like you can now in Scandinavia, without any 
knowledge of the local language, but for now be warned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Traffic is amazingly low&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure all my polish friends will cry in &lt;strong&gt;outrage&lt;/strong&gt; at this but trust me, 
it's nowhere near what it's like to drive in Rome or Naples. That's hell 
on earth compared to Warsaw. There's a reason why we say&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you can drive in Naples, you can drive everywhere&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and it's not because of the very strict driving schools. Seriously, 
traffic is mostly smooth but for a couple of spots at the usual rush 
hours. Finding a parking spot for your car is unbelievably easier than 
back in Italy: in Warsaw's centre, in front of the Palace of Justice, 
you can be sure to find an empty spot at every hour. Nothing of this 
sort can be said for any major italian city; if I had found one like 
that I would consider it &lt;strong&gt;my lucky day&lt;/strong&gt;. Here it seems normal to have a 
few empty spots here and there even in the very centre of the city on a 
weekday morning. I guess because most poles don't have a car (due to 
poverty or choice) and rely on the, mostly &lt;strong&gt;excellent&lt;/strong&gt;, public 
transportation and bike lanes systems. Admittedly, I don't feel the 
need to buy a car anytime soon either. Streets are also very wide and 
there's room to park cars everywhere. But don't try to park your car too 
close to a turn, it will get &lt;strong&gt;confiscated&lt;/strong&gt; in a nanosecond and you will be 
frowned upon by any bystander. I saw it myself and it wasn't nice for 
the driver, as much as it wasn't for the driver who got invested by a 
tram because he didn't clear up the path for it and was also &lt;strong&gt;fined&lt;/strong&gt; 
for interrupting public transportation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trams are &lt;strong&gt;evil&lt;/strong&gt; here, don't mess with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Weather&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talk about the weather last, contrarily to most foreigners (trying to 
be original, see?). I have not yet experienced the &lt;strong&gt;cold polish 
winter&lt;/strong&gt; but for a brief stint last year when I made a supervising trip 
of 5 days. That was enough to give me a good idea though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, it is &lt;strong&gt;cold&lt;/strong&gt;. Grey too. And extremely &lt;strong&gt;windy&lt;/strong&gt;, which is the worst thing 
you can face when on a 50m wide and 2km long street without any covering 
but for leafeless trees. Try to cross a bridge over the Vistula in the 
middle of the winter and I'm sure you will be ready to be sold as frozen 
meat before you reach the other end. &lt;strong&gt;Nobody&lt;/strong&gt; crosses a bridge here in 
winter. Nobody that plans to survive, at least. Often walking out feels 
like a race from a heated place to the next with the prize being 
survival. Once I took the road from the Stadion Narodowy (the football 
stadium) north towards the Praga neighborhood along the river because I 
got off the tram one stop earlier than I intended: &lt;strong&gt;worst decision ever&lt;/strong&gt;. 
It was like 1km or even less but I felt like the poor Athenian soldier 
running back to Athens after Marathon battle. Only with harsh cold and 
strong wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet is getting &lt;strong&gt;better&lt;/strong&gt;. Last winter was below -10°C only for a couple of 
weeks, most of the time was between 0 and -10, which is mild here. 
Spring has been pretty ok and sunny and this summer has been universally 
considered as one of the warmest ever. It felt like Italy a handful of 
days. We have hope this winter won't be that bad after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it won't, luckily, as I said above, houses are usually very warm. 
Restaurant and bars even more as they put the heating system to the 
maximum out of sheer &lt;strong&gt;hate of winter&lt;/strong&gt;, there's no other possible 
explanation: it is normal to stay in t-shirts inside and then having to 
put 3 layers on before going out. Perfect to get a cold. Which 
considering the &lt;strong&gt;abnormal&lt;/strong&gt; number of pharmacies available seems to be 
quite common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all I'm &lt;strong&gt;enjoying&lt;/strong&gt; my staying in Poland. People are generally very 
nice, educated and respectful. Honest too. The problems I have told of 
above aren't that bad, nothing that would make me decide to go back to 
Italy. Poland at least is improving its shortcomings, Italy has been 
&lt;strong&gt;stagnating&lt;/strong&gt; for decades. Unfortunately, not just the economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S.=for any criticism, correction or outraged messages, feel free to 
mail, comment or @'s me on Twitter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photos courtesy: &lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/flag-of-poland-5611/"&gt;Poland 
Flag&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/paszczak000/"&gt;Vodka&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kitchenwench"&gt;Pierogi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/photobeppus"&gt;Communist 
Blocks&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/koldre"&gt;Bed and 
Cat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="poland"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="moving out"></category><category term="experience"></category></entry><entry><title>A Brief Guide To DuckDuckGo</title><link href="http://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/a-brief-guide-to-duckduckgo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-26T11:44:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-06-26T11:44:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Gianluca Fiore</name></author><id>tag:www.gianlucafiore.it,2015-06-26:/blog/a-brief-guide-to-duckduckgo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Or why you should be using it even if you don't care about &lt;a href="http://donttrack.us/"&gt;privacy&lt;/a&gt; or don't know what a &lt;a href="http://dontbubble.us/"&gt;search engine bubble&lt;/a&gt; may be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's in no way comprehensive nor "the best of". Just what I find more useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;days between today and 02/28/2013&lt;/code&gt; = 16 days. Unfortunately …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Or why you should be using it even if you don't care about &lt;a href="http://donttrack.us/"&gt;privacy&lt;/a&gt; or don't know what a &lt;a href="http://dontbubble.us/"&gt;search engine bubble&lt;/a&gt; may be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's in no way comprehensive nor "the best of". Just what I find more useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;days between today and 02/28/2013&lt;/code&gt; = 16 days. Unfortunately, this uses the US month/day/year format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;18:30 to 19:25&lt;/code&gt; = 55 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;february calendar&lt;/code&gt; = print the calendar for this year's february&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Travel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weather&lt;/code&gt; = weather for your current location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;80100&lt;/code&gt; = search for the map of your postal code. Finds also matching codes in other countries. Or you can specify &lt;code&gt;80100 Germany&lt;/code&gt; to  get the result you want straight away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;florence sunrise&lt;/code&gt; = when does the sun rises in Florence? Here too it works with in the local language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;temp in new york&lt;/code&gt; = current temperature in New York&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Numbers and Math&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;uuid&lt;/code&gt; = generate a random unique identifier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;roman numeral MCCXXII&lt;/code&gt; = convert the roman numeral in arabic. That's 1222, btw&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;md5 whatever&lt;/code&gt; = calculate md5 sum of &lt;code&gt;whatever&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sha whatever&lt;/code&gt; = calculate sha sum of &lt;code&gt;whatever&lt;/code&gt;. Works with &lt;code&gt;sha256&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;sha512&lt;/code&gt; too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;goog&lt;/code&gt; = company and stock data (Google)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;roll 4d12&lt;/code&gt; = simulate rolling 4 d12 dices. D&amp;amp;D fans, rejoice!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;average 10, 33, 54, 70&lt;/code&gt; = 41.75&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;square root of 84&lt;/code&gt; =  9.16515138991168&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;is 765 prime&lt;/code&gt; = find whether a number is prime or not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;random number&lt;/code&gt; = generate a random number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;45 farenheit in celsius&lt;/code&gt; = 7.222. It works also as &lt;code&gt;45 F to C&lt;/code&gt; (shorter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Currency and Finance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;100 usd to eur&lt;/code&gt; = 74.28€&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;usd vs eur&lt;/code&gt; = conversion values between $ and €&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Words&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;0110100001100101011011000110110001101111 to ascii&lt;/code&gt; = binary to ascii conversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;hello in binary&lt;/code&gt; = convert hello to binary. Accepts ascii, numbers and hex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;anagram the ship was sailing&lt;/code&gt; = anagram a phrase. Works in any language but results are rarely meaningful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;lorem ipsum&lt;/code&gt; = generate random text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;detect language merci&lt;/code&gt; = that's french, of course. Works pretty well with local dialects too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;define oxen&lt;/code&gt; = definition for oxen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;spell incospicuous&lt;/code&gt; = check spelling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;random word&lt;/code&gt; = generate a random, english, word. It's possible to specify the range of characters length with &lt;code&gt;random word 5-9&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;chars little test&lt;/code&gt; = how many characters in &lt;code&gt;little test&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;related to cat&lt;/code&gt; = words related to &lt;code&gt;cat&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;synonyms for cat&lt;/code&gt; = find synonyms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Travel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;AZ 107&lt;/code&gt; = flight status by flight code. I found this to be somewhat unreliable but 99% of the queries the first link is the right one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;distance paris to london&lt;/code&gt; = 342km. Works in the local language too (Koln instead of Cologne, Roma instead of Rome etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;time in honolulu&lt;/code&gt; = what time is it in Hawaii?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Entertainment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;monumension album by Enslaved&lt;/code&gt; = info on an album&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Jesus Saves, I Spend song by St. Vincent&lt;/code&gt; = info on a song&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;songs by Metallica&lt;/code&gt; = most popular songs on Last.fm from Metallica&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;imdb Young Frankenstein&lt;/code&gt; = info on a movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;xkcd&lt;/code&gt; = get the latest xkcd comic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cooking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;1 tsp to gram&lt;/code&gt; = how many grams is a teaspoon?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;calories in 100 gr of cottage cheese&lt;/code&gt; = 81 calories. Works with both Imperial/Metric systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;carbs in rice&lt;/code&gt; = how many carbohydrates on average in a rice portion? Works also with fibers, saturated fat, magnesium etc. For more precise calculations use &lt;code&gt;how much fiber in 100gr of salmon&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;nutrition in a kiwi&lt;/code&gt; = detailed nutritional facts about Kiwis. The fruit, that is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;how to mix a Americano&lt;/code&gt; = how to prepare an Americano?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Geek&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;@Donearm&lt;/code&gt; = shows twitter profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;#duckduckgo&lt;/code&gt; = Twitter hashtag search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;google+ Gianluca Fiore&lt;/code&gt; = search for G+ profiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:D&lt;/code&gt; = meaning of the :D emoticon. Not that many are supported but at least the most common are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;password 9 strong&lt;/code&gt; = generate a random password of 9 characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;expand http://dlvr.it/2rwGVR&lt;/code&gt; = expand a shortened url&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;qrcode http://www.google.com&lt;/code&gt; = generate a qrcode for Google homepage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;is duckduckgo.com up?&lt;/code&gt; = is our favourite duck up?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ip address&lt;/code&gt; = show your current IP address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;useragent&lt;/code&gt; = show your browser User-Agent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;unicode €&lt;/code&gt; = unicode codes and name for the any symbol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;U+123a&lt;/code&gt; = what symbol corresponds to this Unicode code?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;#33;&lt;/code&gt; = decode HTML entities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;reddit luajit&lt;/code&gt; = search Reddit posts about LuaJit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;port 23&lt;/code&gt; = TCP port information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;hex color code for dark grey&lt;/code&gt; = get RGB, HSL and CMYB values for a colour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;#368798&lt;/code&gt; = find colour from its HEX code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;urlencode still$&lt;/code&gt; = urlencode a string (still%24 in this case). More escape codes with &lt;code&gt;url escape&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bitly url&lt;/code&gt; = shortens url with bit.ly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gravatar email&lt;/code&gt; = find Gravatar for an email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;public dns&lt;/code&gt; = list common public DNS servers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;64.200.12.10&lt;/code&gt; = IP address lookup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;*nix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;man ctags&lt;/code&gt; = manpage for ctags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;crontab 10 0 * 1 *&lt;/code&gt; = when a task is being scheduled by cron?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;epoch&lt;/code&gt; = time since the Unix epoch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;12343435 time&lt;/code&gt; = convert a Unix epoch to date. Also &lt;code&gt;unix time 12343435&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Programming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;http status 102&lt;/code&gt; = reference for http status codes. More generally, it accepts various query for many languages. For example, &lt;code&gt;lua function&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;c #define&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;python urllib2&lt;/code&gt; all return, more or less, what you'd expect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;emacs C-t&lt;/code&gt; = Emacs reference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;html span&lt;/code&gt; = html entities reference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git cherry-pick&lt;/code&gt; = git manpage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;lua jobs&lt;/code&gt; = Github Jobs search (only 1 for lua, me sad...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;!Bang Syntax&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are a bit different since they don't make queries on DuckDuckGo but use other websites to search &lt;em&gt;into&lt;/em&gt;. In general, it's like using &lt;code&gt;site:http://www.mysite.com query&lt;/code&gt;, only with far less keystrokes.&lt;br&gt;
There are a whole bunch of them. Like, &lt;a href="https://duckduckgo.com/bang.html"&gt;a lot&lt;/a&gt;. Do browse that list, I'm sure there are many sites that you use to browse to in order to make a search with their internal search form but with these you can do it directly from DuckDuckGo main page. Extremely handy when you already know where to look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourites are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!tumblr&lt;/code&gt; = search on Tumblr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!h33t&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;!torrent&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;!torrentz&lt;/code&gt; = torrent search. You know, legal stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!firefox&lt;/code&gt; = search Firefox add-ons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!vim&lt;/code&gt; = search on vim.org. I use it all the time to know what a new plugin does&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!appbrain&lt;/code&gt; = Android app search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!gist&lt;/code&gt; = Gists search. Some great gems can be found among gists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!github&lt;/code&gt; = repository search on Github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!python&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;!python3&lt;/code&gt; = search in Python (2 or 3) documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!xdaf&lt;/code&gt; = xda-developers.com forum search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!so&lt;/code&gt; = Stackoverflow. Best way to get a quick answer to a programming problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!unix&lt;/code&gt; = search in *nix source code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!distro&lt;/code&gt; = lookup a Linux distribution on distrowatch.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!archlinux&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;!archwiki&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;!aur&lt;/code&gt; = search, respectively, on Archlinux forum, wiki and among AUR packages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!amit&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;!amuk&lt;/code&gt; = Amazon search (It and Uk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!cstheory&lt;/code&gt; = computer science questions and answers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!lonelyplanet&lt;/code&gt; = Lonely Planet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!tripadvisor&lt;/code&gt; = TripAdvisor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!bmaps&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;!map&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;!osm&lt;/code&gt; = Map searches (Bing, Google and OpenStreet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!urban&lt;/code&gt; = slang words search on Urban Dictionary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!allmusic&lt;/code&gt; = Allmusic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!define&lt;/code&gt; = Define a word&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;!spanishdict&lt;/code&gt; = From spanish to english&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="search engine"></category><category term="duckduckgo"></category><category term="guide"></category></entry></feed>