<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Football on Gianluca Fiore</title>
    <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/football/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Football on Gianluca Fiore</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 11:04:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/football/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Pelé</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/on-pele/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 11:04:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/on-pele/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-king-and-the-god-are-gone&#34;&gt;The King and the God are gone&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pelé was a totem. And a scary one at that. For a kid growing up in Naples during the 80s, Pelé was not a tangible experience but a myth already. Somebody who we would all compare to, as the archetype of the great footballer from South America.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He was a scary figure. Scary because for a city being dragged to the top of the league, twice, by Maradona, Pelé was the only one we could possibly believe being better than our God, Diego. Fans used to chant &amp;ldquo;Maradona is better than Pelé&amp;rdquo; and, while perhaps true, it was a chant born out of fear rather than proud.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Is My Team Playing?</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/when-is-my-team-playing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 16:34:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/when-is-my-team-playing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a football fan, I&amp;rsquo;m always on the lookout for informations about my favourite teams. I have more than one so the search is not immediate. Most of the time, using multiple websites, I have to click multiple times to see the league standings&amp;rsquo; and where is my team is at the moment. Worse, a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; of sport newspapers on the internet don&amp;rsquo;t immediately give you info about the next match of your team, nor you are sure if the time given is accurate to your timezone. Uk media will obviously give times in the Greenwich time while German in Berlin time and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s is not then immediate to have a simple and clear overview of what are the next matches and what is the league situation of a given team.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
