<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>javascript on Gianluca Fiore</title>
    <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in javascript on Gianluca Fiore</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 16:34:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>When Is My Team Playing?</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/when-is-my-team-playing-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 16:34:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/when-is-my-team-playing-presentation/</guid>
      <description>As a football fan, I&amp;rsquo;m always on the lookout for informations about my favourite teams. I have more than one so the search is not immediate. Most of the time, using multiple websites, I have to click multiple times to see the league standings&amp;rsquo; and where is my team is at the moment. Worse, a lot of sport newspapers on the internet don&amp;rsquo;t immediately give you info about the next match of your team, nor you are sure if the time given is accurate to your timezone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Is The Best Pizza In The World?</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/where-is-the-best-pizza-in-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 10:54:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/where-is-the-best-pizza-in-the-world/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago I found the pizza repository of Steve Kinney, a project to list all the best pizzerias around the world. As a fan of pizza and being born in the hometown of it (Naples for those unaware), I started contributing to it pizzerias in Italy and Poland mostly that I knew by first-hand experience were very good.
To make a longer story short, slowly the contributions piled up and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t satisfied with a few technical solutions adopted, mainly the use of Ruby and implementing the list of pizzerias in Markdown in the Readme file.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>