<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>development on Gianluca Fiore</title>
    <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in development on Gianluca Fiore</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 11:24:03 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.gianlucafiore.it/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Your First Year In Code</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/your-first-year-in-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 11:24:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/your-first-year-in-code/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been surprised, even amused, by the show of affection friends show in myself. Caring about myself has never been a high priority for me, I admit, so I emotionally recoil whenever an external being cares about my wellbeing more than me. I cannot comprehend it, on an emotional level of course as logically it is natural for friends to care about each other.
What surprises me the most is the long-lasting effect I may have on people who I have barely crossed their paths during my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I Know as of 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/things-i-know-as-of-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 18:11:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/things-i-know-as-of-2018/</guid>
      <description>It honestly came as a surprise a post on Overreacted by Dan Abramov. He lists all the things he doesn&amp;rsquo;t know as of 2018, in an attempt to &amp;ldquo;devalue&amp;rdquo; in the eyes of newbies any experienced developer by showing off the gaps in knowledge that usually we take for granted, expecially from those developers that work for big companies and who went through a harder interview process. Considering the number of likes and retweets the post received, I&amp;rsquo;m far from being the only one surprised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freecodecamp</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/freecodecamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 21:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/freecodecamp/</guid>
      <description>Frontend development was never my area. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been more of a Backend/System Administrator. I&amp;rsquo;ve never truly grokked the idea of events, DOM, making requests elsewhere and things running outside my machine, without me giving precise instruction when to run and what arguments to accept.
Yet it&amp;rsquo;s 2018 and Javascript permeates the programming world, whether we like it or not. Thus I was looking for a new challenge to keep me motivated to learn throughout the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Isn&#39;t Easy</title>
      <link>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/programming-isnt-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 14:44:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gianlucafiore.it/blog/programming-isnt-easy/</guid>
      <description>I was reading, as usual, Scott Hanselman&amp;rsquo;s blog and couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more on his complaining on the recent WWDC keynote asserting that programming is easy. From his post:
 When we tell folks - kids or otherwise - that programming is easy, what will they think when it gets difficult? And it will get difficult. That&amp;rsquo;s where people find themselves saying &amp;ldquo;well, I guess I&amp;rsquo;m not wired for coding. It&amp;rsquo;s just not for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>